<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?><sst xmlns="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/spreadsheetml/2006/main" count="398" uniqueCount="398"><si><t>Frequently used/Derived variables (Finance) - Revenues and expenditures: Fiscal year 2023</t></si><si><t>(Final/revised release)</t></si><si><t>Filename</t></si><si><t>DRVF2023</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Provisional release:</t></si><si><t>January 2025</t></si><si><t>DRVF2023_RV</t></si><si><t>January 2026</t></si><si><t>Overview</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Table includes the following financial indicator variables: percent of core revenues by source of revenue; percent of core expenses by expense functional categories; core revenues per full-time equivalent enrollment by source of revenues; core expenses per full-time equivalent enrollment by expense categories; expenses for salaries, wages, and benefits as a percent of total expenses, by expense categories;  There is a set of indicators for GASB, FASB and for-profit institutions. Frequently used derived variables may include data for child campuses derived from allocation factors that are reported by the parent institution. Parent/child indicators can be found in table flags2023.</t></si><si><t>Note</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">IPEDS data, including provisional release data and final release data, adhere to rigorous quality control procedures established by NCES. Data are imputed for nonresponding institutions. Provisional release data are used for First Look  web tables. Final release data include revisions to the provisional release data that have been made by institutions during the subsequent data collection year. While the final release data offer  the most up to date data, these data may not match tables from the First Look web tables based on provisional release data.</t></si><si><t>Contents of spreadsheet</t></si><si><t>Varlist</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Variable list: Lists all variables in the table. Includes the variable name, variable label and the Data type, format and maximum field width of each variable.  The data type describes a variable as either a numeric (N) or Alphanumeric (A) and the format of a variable defines a variable as either continuous (Cont.) or categorical (Disc).  It all also lists the variable name of all imputation flag variables for each continuous variable. Imputation flag variable describes whether a value for the corresponding variable was reported, imputed or not applicable.</t></si><si><t>Description</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Long description or glossary definition of a variable. </t></si><si><t>Statistics</t></si><si><t>This worksheet lists the sum, mean, minimum and maximum values of all continuous variables in the data file. (Provisional release)</t></si><si><t>StatisticsRV</t></si><si><t>This worksheet lists the sum, mean, minimum and maximum values of all continuous variables in the data file. (Final/revised release)</t></si><si><t>varNumber</t></si><si><t>varName</t></si><si><t>DataType</t></si><si><t>FieldWidth</t></si><si><t>format</t></si><si><t>imputationvar</t></si><si><t>varTitle</t></si><si><t>UNITID</t></si><si><t>N</t></si><si><t>Cont</t></si><si><t></t></si><si><t>Unique identification number of the institution</t></si><si><t>F1CORREV</t></si><si><t>Core revenues, total dollars (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1TUFEPC</t></si><si><t>Tuition and fees as a percent of core revenues (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1STAPPC</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">State appropriations as percent of core revenues  (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1LCAPPC</t></si><si><t>Local appropriations as a percent of core revenues (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1GVGCPC</t></si><si><t>Government grants and contracts as a percent of core revenues (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1PGGCPC</t></si><si><t>Private gifts, grants, and contracts as a percent of core revenues (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1INVRPC</t></si><si><t>Investment return as a percent of core revenues (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1OTRVPC</t></si><si><t>Other revenues as a percent of core revenues (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1TUFEFT</t></si><si><t>Revenues from tuition and fees per FTE (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1STAPFT</t></si><si><t>Revenues from state appropriations per FTE (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1LCAPFT</t></si><si><t>Revenues from local appropriations per FTE (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1GVGCFT</t></si><si><t>Revenues from government grants and contracts per FTE (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1PGGCFT</t></si><si><t>Revenues from private gifts, grants, and contracts per FTE (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1INVRFT</t></si><si><t>Revenues from investment return per FTE (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1OTRVFT</t></si><si><t>Other core revenues per FTE (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1COREXP</t></si><si><t>Core expenses, total dollars (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1INSTFT</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Instruction expenses per FTE  (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1RSRCFT</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Research expenses per FTE  (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1PBSVFT</t></si><si><t>Public service expenses per FTE (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1ACSPFT</t></si><si><t>Academic support expenses per FTE (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1STSVFT</t></si><si><t>Student service expenses per FTE (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1INSUFT</t></si><si><t>Institutional support expenses per FTE (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1OTEXFT</t></si><si><t>All other core expenses per FTE (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1INSTPC</t></si><si><t>Instruction expenses as a percent of total core expenses (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1RSRCPC</t></si><si><t>Research expenses as a percent of total core expenses (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1PBSVPC</t></si><si><t>Public service expenses as a percent of total core expenses (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1ACSPPC</t></si><si><t>Academic support expenses as a percent of total core expenses (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1STSVPC</t></si><si><t>Student service expenses as a percent of total core expenses (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1INSUPC</t></si><si><t>Institutional support expenses as a percent of total core expenses (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1OTEXPC</t></si><si><t>Other core expenses as a percent of total core expenses (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1SWINSP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for instruction as a percent of total expenses for instruction (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1SWRSRP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for research as a percent of total expenses for research (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1SWPBSP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for public service as a percent of total expenses for public service (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1SWACSP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for academic support as a percent of total expenses for academic support (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1SWSTSP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for student services as a percent of total expenses for student services (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1SWISPP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for institutional support as a percent of total expenses for institutional support (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1SWOTEP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for other core expense functions as a percent of total expenses for other core expense functions (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1SWCREP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for core expenses as a percent of total core expenses (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1ENDMFT</t></si><si><t>Endowment assets (year end) per FTE enrollment (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1SAFBPC</t></si><si><t>Total salaries, wages, and benefits as a percent of total expenses (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1SALRPC</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">N </t></si><si><t>Total salaries and wages as a percent of total expenses (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F1EQUITR</t></si><si><t>Equity ratio (GASB)</t></si><si><t>F2CORREV</t></si><si><t>Core revenues, total dollars (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2TUFEPC</t></si><si><t>Tuition and fees as a percent of core revenues (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2GVGCPC</t></si><si><t>Government grants and contracts as a percent of core revenues (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2PGGCPC</t></si><si><t>Private gifts, grants, contracts/contributions from affiliated entities as a percent of core revenues (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2INVRPC</t></si><si><t>Investment return as a percent of core revenues (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2OTRVPC</t></si><si><t>Other revenues as a percent of core revenues (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2TUFEFT</t></si><si><t>Revenues from tuition and fees per FTE (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2GVGCFT</t></si><si><t>Revenues from government grants and contracts per FTE (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2PGGCFT</t></si><si><t>Revenues from private gifts, grants, contracts/contributions from affiliated entities per FTE (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2INVRFT</t></si><si><t>Revenues from investment return per FTE (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2OTRVFT</t></si><si><t>Other core revenues per FTE (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2COREXP</t></si><si><t>Core expenses, total dollars (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2INSTFT</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Instruction expenses per FTE  (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2RSRCFT</t></si><si><t>Research expenses per FTE (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2PBSVFT</t></si><si><t>Public service expenses per FTE (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2ACSPFT</t></si><si><t>Academic support expenses per FTE (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2STSVFT</t></si><si><t>Student service expenses per FTE (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2INSUFT</t></si><si><t>Institutional support expenses per FTE (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2OTEXFT</t></si><si><t>All other core expenses per FTE (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2INSTPC</t></si><si><t>Instruction expenses as a percent of total core expenses (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2RSRCPC</t></si><si><t>Research expenses as a percent of total core expenses (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2PBSVPC</t></si><si><t>Public service expenses as a percent of total core expenses (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2ACSPPC</t></si><si><t>Academic support expenses as a percent of total core expenses (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2STSVPC</t></si><si><t>Student service expenses as a percent of total core expenses (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2INSUPC</t></si><si><t>Institutional support expenses as a percent of total core expenses (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2OTEXPC</t></si><si><t>Other core expenses as a percent of total core expenses (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2SWINSP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for instruction as a percent of total expenses for instruction (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2SWRSRP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for research as a percent of total expenses for research (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2SWPBSP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for public service as a percent of total expenses for public service (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2SWACSP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for academic support as a percent of total expenses for academic support (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2SWSTSP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for student services as a percent of total expenses for student services (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2SWISPP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for institutional support as a percent of total expenses for institutional support (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2SWOTEP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for other core expense functions as a percent of total expenses for other core expense functions (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2SWCREP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for core expenses as a percent of total core expenses (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2ENDMFT</t></si><si><t>Endowment assets (year end) per FTE enrollment (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2SAFBPC</t></si><si><t>Total salaries, wages, and benefits as a percent of total expenses (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2SALRPC</t></si><si><t>Total salaries and wages as a percent of total expenses (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F2EQUITR</t></si><si><t>Equity ratio (FASB)</t></si><si><t>F3CORREV</t></si><si><t>Core revenues, total dollars (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3TUFEPC</t></si><si><t>Tuition and fees as a percent of core revenues (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3GVGCPC</t></si><si><t>Government grants and contracts as a percent of core revenues (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3PGGCPC</t></si><si><t>Private gifts, grants, contracts as a percent of core revenues (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3INVRPC</t></si><si><t>Investment return as a percent of core revenues (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3SSEAPC</t></si><si><t>Sales and services of educational activities as a percent of core revenues (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3OTRVPC</t></si><si><t>Other revenues as a percent of core revenues (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3TUFEFT</t></si><si><t>Revenues from tuition and fees per FTE (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3GVGCFT</t></si><si><t>Revenues from government grants and contracts per FTE (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3PGGCFT</t></si><si><t>Revenues from private gifts, grants, contracts per FTE (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3INVRFT</t></si><si><t>Revenues from investment return per FTE (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3SSEAFT</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Revenues from sales and services of educational activities per FTE  (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3OTRVFT</t></si><si><t>Other core revenues per FTE (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3COREXP</t></si><si><t>Core expenses, total dollars (for-profit institutons)</t></si><si><t>F3INSTFT</t></si><si><t>Instruction expenses per FTE (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3RSRCFT</t></si><si><t>Research expenses per FTE (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3PBSVFT</t></si><si><t>Public service expenses per FTE (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3ACSPFT</t></si><si><t>Academic support expenses per FTE (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3STSVFT</t></si><si><t>Student service expenses per FTE (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3INSUFT</t></si><si><t>Institutional support expenses per FTE (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3OTEXFT</t></si><si><t>All other core expenses per FTE (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3INSTPC</t></si><si><t>Instruction expenses as a percent of total core expenses (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3RSRCPC</t></si><si><t>Research expenses as a percent of total core expenses (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3PBSVPC</t></si><si><t>Public service expenses as a percent of total core expenses (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3ACSPPC</t></si><si><t>Academic support expenses as a percent of total core expenses (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3STSVPC</t></si><si><t>Student service expenses as a percent of total core expenses (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3INSUPC</t></si><si><t>Institutional support expenses as a percent of total core expenses (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3OTEXPC</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Other core expenses as a percent of total  core expenses (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3SWINSP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for instruction as a percent of total expenses for instruction (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3SWRSRP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for research as a percent of total expenses for research (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3SWPBSP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for public service as a percent of total expenses for public service (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3SWACSP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for academic support as a percent of total expenses for academic support (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3SWSTSP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for student services as a percent of total expenses for student services (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3SWISPP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for institutional support as a percent of total expenses for institutional support (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3SWOTEP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for other core expense functions as a percent of total expenses for other core expense functions (for-profit)</t></si><si><t>F3SWCREP</t></si><si><t>Salaries and wages for core expenses as a percent of total core expenses (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3SAFBPC</t></si><si><t>Total salaries, wages, and benefits as a percent of total expenses (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3SALRPC</t></si><si><t>Total salaries and wages as a percent of total expenses (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>F3EQUITR</t></si><si><t>Equity ratio (for-profit institutions)</t></si><si><t>longDescription</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Core revenues,total dollars for public institutions using  GASB 34/35 standard are derived by adding revenues from the following sources:_x000D_
_x0009__x000D_
 Tuition and fees revenues (F1B01)_x000D_
 State government appropriation revenues F1B11  _x000D_
 Local government appropriation revenues F1B12  _x000D_
 Federal operating grants and contracts (F1B02)_x000D_
 State operating grants and contracts (F1B03)_x000D_
 Local operating grants and contracts (F1B04)_x000D_
 Other operating sources (F1B08)_x000D_
 Federal appropriations (F1B10)_x000D_
 Federal nonoperating grants (F1B13)_x000D_
 State nonoperating grants (F1B14)_x000D_
 Local nonoperating grants (F1B15)_x000D_
 Gifts, including contributions from affiliated  organizations (F1B16)_x000D_
 Investment income (F1B17)_x000D_
 Other nonoperating revenues (F1B18)_x000D_
 Total other revenues and additions (F1B24)_x000D_
 Sales and services of educational activities (F1B26)_x000D_
_x000D_
For glossary definitions of the above finance terms see variables listed under the Finance survey.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Tuition and fees as a percent of core revenues for public institutions using  GASB 34/35 standard is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Tuition and fees revenues (F1B01) divided by total core revenues (F1CORREV)_x000D_
_x000D_
Tuition and fees (revenues) (F1B01) -  Revenues from all tuition and fees assessed against students (net of refunds and discounts and allowances) for educational purposes. If tuition or fees are remitted to the state as an offset to the state appropriation, the total of such tuition or fees are deducted from the total state appropriation and added to the total for tuition and fees.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">State appropriations as a percent of core revenues for public institutions using GASB 34/35 is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
State appropriations (F1B11) divided by total core revenues (F1CORREV)_x000D_
_x000D_
State appropriations are amounts received by the institution through acts of a state legislative body, except grants and contracts and capital appropriations. Funds reported in this category are for meeting current operating expenses, not for specific projects or programs.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Local appropriations as a percent of core revenues for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Local appropriations (F1B12) divided by total core revenues (F1CORREV)_x000D_
_x000D_
Local appropriations, education district taxes, and similar support - Local appropriations are government appropriations made by a governmental entity below the state level. Education district taxes include all tax revenues assessed directly by an institution or on behalf of an institution when the institution will receive the exact amount collected. These revenues also include similar revenues that result from actions of local governments or citizens (such as through a referendum) that result in receipt by the institution of revenues based on collections of other taxes or resources (sales taxes, gambling taxes, etc.).</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Government grants and contracts as a percent of core revenues for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Government grants and contracts is equal to the sum of _x000D_
_x000D_
Federal operating grants and contracts (F1B02)_x000D_
State operating grants and contracts (F1B03)_x000D_
Local operating grants and contracts (F1B04A)_x000D_
Federal nonoperating grants (F1B13)_x000D_
State nonoperating grants (F1B14)_x000D_
Local nonperating grants (F1B15)_x000D_
_x000D_
Government grants and contract revenues is then divided by total core revenues (F1CORREV)_x000D_
_x000D_
Government grants and contracts (revenues) - Revenues from governmental agencies that are for specific research projects, other types of programs , or for general institutional operations (if not government appropriations). Examples are research projects, training programs, student financial assistance, and similar activities for which amounts are received or expenses are reimbursable under the terms of a grant or contract, including amounts to cover both direct and indirect expenses. Includes Pell Grants and reimbursement for costs of administering federal financial aid programs. Grants and contracts should be classified to identify the governmental level - federal, state, or local - funding the grant or contract to the institution; grants and contracts from other sources are classified as nongovernmental grants and contracts. GASB institutions are required to classify in financial reports such grants and contracts as either operating or nonoperating.  _x000D_
_x000D_
Operating - GASB requires that revenues and expenses be separated between operating and nonoperating. Operating revenues and expenses result from providing goods and services. Operating transactions are incurred in the course of the operating activities of the institution _x000D_
_x000D_
Nonoperating - GASB requires that revenues and expenses be separated between operating and nonoperating. Operating revenues and expenses result from providing goods and services. Nonoperating activities are those outside the activities that are part of the operating activities of the institution. Most government appropriations are nonoperating because they are not generated by the operations of the institution. Investment income is nonoperating in most instances because institutions are not engaged in investing as an operating activity. Gifts are defined as nonoperating. Nonexchange transactions generate nonoperating revenues.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Private gifts, grants, and contracts as a percent of core revenues (GASB)_x000D_
_x000D_
Private gifts, grants, and contracts is the sum of_x000D_
_x000D_
Private operating grants and contracts (F1B04B)_x000D_
Gifts, including contributions from affiliated organizations (F1B16)_x000D_
_x000D_
Private gifts, grants, and contracts is then divided by total core revenues (F1CORREV)_x000D_
_x000D_
Private operating grants and contracts - Revenues from nongovernmental agencies and organizations that are for specific research projects or other types of programs and that are classified as operating revenues. Examples are research projects and similar activities for which amounts are received or expenditures are reimbursable under the terms of a grant or contract._x000D_
_x000D_
Gifts, including contributions from affiliated organizations - Revenues from private donors for which no legal consideration is provided; these would be nonexchange transactions as defined in GASB Statement No. 33 Accounting and Financial Reporting for Nonexchange Transactions. Includes all gifts or contributions to the institution except those classified as additions to permanent endowments or capital grants &amp; gifts. Includes gifts from affiliated organizations. Includes the amount of contributed services recognized by the institution. Amounts from capital grants and contracts are not included.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Investment return as a percent of core revenues (GASB) is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Investment return (F1B17) is divided by total core revenues (F1CORREV)_x000D_
_x000D_
Investment income -  Revenues derived from the institution's investments, including investments of endowment funds. Such income may take the form of interest income, dividend income, rental income or royalty income and includes both realized and unrealized gains and losses</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Other core revenues as a percent of total core revenues for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standard is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Other core revenues is equal to the sum of:_x000D_
_x000D_
Other operating sources (F1B08)_x000D_
Federal appropriations (F1B10)_x000D_
Other nonoperating revenues (F1B18)_x000D_
Total other revenues and additions (F1B24)_x000D_
_x000D_
Other core revenues is then divided by total core revenues (F1CORREV)_x000D_
_x000D_
For glossary definitions of the above finance terms see variables listed under the Finance survey.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Revenues from tuition and fees per FTE enrollment for public institutions using  GASB 34/35 standard is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Tuition and fees revenues (F1B01) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
Tuition and fees (revenues) (F1B01) -  Revenues from all tuition and fees assessed against students (net of refunds and discounts and allowances) for educational purposes. If tuition or fees are remitted to the state as an offset to the state appropriation, the total of such tuition or fees are deducted from the total state appropriation and added to the total for tuition and fees._x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Revenues from State appropriations per FTE enrollment for public institutions using GASB 34/35 is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
State appropriations (F1B11) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
State appropriations are amounts received by the institution through acts of a state legislative body, except grants and contracts and capital appropriations. Funds reported in this category are for meeting current operating expenses, not for specific projects or programs._x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Revenues from local appropriations per FTE enrollment for public institutions using GASB 34/35 is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Local appropriations (F1B12) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
Local appropriations, education district taxes, and similar support - Local appropriations are government appropriations made by a governmental entity below the state level. Education district taxes include all tax revenues assessed directly by an institution or on behalf of an institution when the institution will receive the exact amount collected. These revenues also include similar revenues that result from actions of local governments or citizens (such as through a referendum) that result in receipt by the institution of revenues based on collections of other taxes or resources (sales taxes, gambling taxes, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Revenues from government grants and contracts per FTE enrollment for public institutions using GASB 34/35 is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Government grants and contracts is equal to the sum of _x000D_
_x000D_
Federal operating grants and contracts (F1B02)_x000D_
State operating grants and contracts (F1B03)_x000D_
Local operating grants and contracts (F1B04A)_x000D_
Federal nonoperating grants (F1B13)_x000D_
State nonoperating grants (F1B14)_x000D_
Local nonperating grants (F1B15)_x000D_
_x000D_
Government grants and contract revenues is then divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
Government grants and contracts (revenues) - Revenues from governmental agencies that are for specific research projects, other types of programs , or for general institutional operations (if not government appropriations). Examples are research projects, training programs, student financial assistance, and similar activities for which amounts are received or expenses are reimbursable under the terms of a grant or contract, including amounts to cover both direct and indirect expenses. Includes Pell Grants and reimbursement for costs of administering federal financial aid programs. Grants and contracts should be classified to identify the governmental level - federal, state, or local - funding the grant or contract to the institution; grants and contracts from other sources are classified as nongovernmental grants and contracts. GASB institutions are required to classify in financial reports such grants and contracts as either operating or nonoperating.  _x000D_
_x000D_
Operating - GASB requires that revenues and expenses be separated between operating and nonoperating. Operating revenues and expenses result from providing goods and services. Operating transactions are incurred in the course of the operating activities of the institution _x000D_
_x000D_
Nonoperating - GASB requires that revenues and expenses be separated between operating and nonoperating. Operating revenues and expenses result from providing goods and services. Nonoperating activities are those outside the activities that are part of the operating activities of the institution. Most government appropriations are nonoperating because they are not generated by the operations of the institution. Investment income is nonoperating in most instances because institutions are not engaged in investing as an operating activity. Gifts are defined as nonoperating. Nonexchange transactions generate nonoperating revenues._x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Revenues from private gifts, grants, and contracts per FTE (GASB) is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Private gifts, grants, and contracts is the sum of_x000D_
_x000D_
Private operating grants and contracts (F1B04B)_x000D_
Gifts, including contributions from affiliated organizations (F1B16)_x000D_
_x000D_
Private gifts, grants, and contracts is then divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
Private operating grants and contracts - Revenues from nongovernmental agencies and organizations that are for specific research projects or other types of programs and that are classified as operating revenues. Examples are research projects and similar activities for which amounts are received or expenditures are reimbursable under the terms of a grant or contract._x000D_
_x000D_
Gifts, including contributions from affiliated organizations - Revenues from private donors for which no legal consideration is provided; these would be nonexchange transactions as defined in GASB Statement No. 33 Accounting and Financial Reporting for Nonexchange Transactions. Includes all gifts or contributions to the institution except those classified as additions to permanent endowments or capital grants &amp; gifts. Includes gifts from affiliated organizations. Includes the amount of contributed services recognized by the institution. Amounts from capital grants and contracts are not included.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Revenues from investment return per FTE (GASB) is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Investment return (F1B17) is divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
Investment income -  Revenues derived from the institution's investments, including investments of endowment funds. Such income may take the form of interest income, dividend income, rental income or royalty income and includes both realized and unrealized gains and losses</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Revenues from other core revenue sources per FTE enrollment for public institutions using GASB 34/35 is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Other core revenues is equal to the sum of:_x000D_
_x000D_
Other operating sources (F1B08)_x000D_
Federal appropriations (F1B10)_x000D_
Other nonoperating revenues (F1B18)_x000D_
Total other revenues and additions (F1B24)_x000D_
_x000D_
Other core revenues is then divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment._x000D_
For glossary definitions of the above finance terms see variables listed under the Finance survey.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Core expenses,total dollars for public institutions using  GASB 34/35 standard are derived by adding expenses for the following functions:_x000D_
_x000D_
 Instruction (F1C011)_x000D_
 Research (F1C021)_x000D_
 Public service (F1C031)_x000D_
 Academic support (F1C051) _x000D_
 Student services (F1C061)_x000D_
 Institutional support (F1C071)_x000D_
 Scholarships and fellowships expenses (F1C101) _x000D_
 Other expenses and deductions (F1C141)_x000D_
 _x000D_
 _x000D_
For glossary definitions of the above finance terms see variables listed under the Finance survey.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Instruction expenses per FTE enrollment for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Instruction expenses (F1C011) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
Instruction - A functional expense category that includes expenses of the colleges, schools, departments, and other instructional divisions of the institution and expenses for departmental research and public service that are not separately budgeted. Includes general academic instruction, occupational and vocational instruction, community education, preparatory and adult basic education, and regular, special, and extension sessions. Also includes expenses for both credit and non-credit activities. Excludes expenses for academic administration where the primary function is administration (e.g., academic deans). Information technology expenses related to instructional activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources are included (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support). FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense. _x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Research expenses per FTE enrollment for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Research expenses (F1C021) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
Research (expense) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for activities specifically organized to produce research outcomes and commissioned by an agency either external to the institution or separately budgeted by an organizational unit within the institution. The category includes institutes and research centers, and individual and project research. This function does not include nonresearch sponsored programs (e.g., training programs). Also included are information technology expenses related to research activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support.) FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation &amp; maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation &amp; maintenance of plant or interest but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours).</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Public service expenses per FTE enrollment for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Public service expenses (F1C031) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
Public service (expense) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for activities established primarily to provide noninstructional services beneficial to individuals and groups external to the institution. Examples are conferences, institutes, general advisory service, reference bureaus, and similar services provided to particular sectors of the community. This function includes expenses for community services, cooperative extension services, and public broadcasting services. Also includes information technology expenses related to the public service activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support). FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Academic support expenses per FTE enrollment for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Academic support (F1C051) expenses divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
 _x000D_
Academic support  A functional expense category that includes expenses of activities and services that support the institution's primary missions of instruction, research, and public service. It includes the retention, preservation, and display of educational materials (for example, libraries, museums, and galleries); organized activities that provide support services to the academic functions of the institution (such as a demonstration school associated with a college of education or veterinary and dental clinics if their primary purpose is to support the instructional program); media such as audiovisual services; academic administration (including academic deans but not department chairpersons); and formally organized and separately budgeted academic personnel development and course and curriculum development expenses. Also included are information technology expenses related to academic support activities; if an institution does not separately budget and expense information technology resources, the costs associated with the three primary programs will be applied to this function and the remainder to institutional support. Under FASB standards this includes actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. Under GASB standards this does not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest but may include depreciation expense. _x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Student services expenses per FTE enrollment for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Student service expenses (F1C061) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
Student services (expenses) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for admissions, registrar activities, and activities whose primary purpose is to contribute to students emotional and physical well - being and to their intellectual, cultural, and social development outside the context of the formal instructional program. Examples include student activities, cultural events, student newspapers, intramural athletics, student organizations, supplemental instruction outside the normal administration, and student records. Intercollegiate athletics and student health services may also be included except when operated as self - supporting auxiliary enterprises. Also may include information technology expenses related to student service activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources(otherwise these expenses are included in institutional support.) FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense.  _x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Institutional support expenses per FTE enrollment for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Institutional support expenses (F1C071) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN) _x000D_
_x000D_
Institutional support - A functional expense category that includes expenses for the day-to-day operational support of the institution. Includes expenses for general administrative services, central executive-level activities concerned with management and long range planning, legal and fiscal operations, space management, employee personnel and records, logistical services such as purchasing and printing, and public relations and development. Also includes information technology expenses related to institutional support activities. If an institution does not separately budget and expense information technology resources, the costs associated with student services and operation and maintenance of plant will also be applied to this function. FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">All other core expenses per FTE enrollment for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Other core expenses is equal to the sum of expenses for the following functions:_x000D_
 _x000D_
Scholarships and fellowships expenses (F1C101) _x000D_
Other expenses and deductions (F1C141)_x000D_
_x000D_
Other core expenses is then divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment._x000D_
For glossary definitions of the above finance terms see variables listed under the Finance survey.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Instruction expenses as a percent of total core expenses for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Instruction expenses (F1C011) divided by total core expenses (F1COREXP)_x000D_
_x000D_
Instruction - A functional expense category that includes expenses of the colleges, schools, departments, and other instructional divisions of the institution and expenses for departmental research and public service that are not separately budgeted. Includes general academic instruction, occupational and vocational instruction, community education, preparatory and adult basic education, and regular, special, and extension sessions. Also includes expenses for both credit and non-credit activities. Excludes expenses for academic administration where the primary function is administration (e.g., academic deans). Information technology expenses related to instructional activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources are included (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support). FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Research expenses as a percent of total core expenses for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Research expenses (F1C021) divided by total core expenses (F1COREXP)_x000D_
_x000D_
Research (expense) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for activities specifically organized to produce research outcomes and commissioned by an agency either external to the institution or separately budgeted by an organizational unit within the institution. The category includes institutes and research centers, and individual and project research. This function does not include nonresearch sponsored programs (e.g., training programs). Also included are information technology expenses related to research activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support.) FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation &amp; maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation &amp; maintenance of plant or interest but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Public service expenses as a percent of total core expenses  for public  institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Public service expenses (F1C031) divided by total core expenses (F1COREXP)_x000D_
_x000D_
Public service (expense) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for activities established primarily to provide noninstructional services beneficial to individuals and groups external to the institution. Examples are conferences, institutes, general advisory service, reference bureaus, and similar services provided to particular sectors of the community. This function includes expenses for community services, cooperative extension services, and public broadcasting services. Also includes information technology expenses related to the public service activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support). FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Academic support expenses as a percent of total core expenses for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Academic support (F1C051) expenses divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (F1COREXP)_x000D_
 _x000D_
Academic support  A functional expense category that includes expenses of activities and services that support the institution's primary missions of instruction, research, and public service. It includes the retention, preservation, and display of educational materials (for example, libraries, museums, and galleries); organized activities that provide support services to the academic functions of the institution (such as a demonstration school associated with a college of education or veterinary and dental clinics if their primary purpose is to support the instructional program); media such as audiovisual services; academic administration (including academic deans but not department chairpersons); and formally organized and separately budgeted academic personnel development and course and curriculum development expenses. Also included are information technology expenses related to academic support activities; if an institution does not separately budget and expense information technology resources, the costs associated with the three primary programs will be applied to this function and the remainder to institutional support. Under FASB standards this includes actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. Under GASB standards this does not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest but may include depreciation expense.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Student services expenses as a percent of total core expenses for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Student service expenses (F1C061) divided by total core expenses (F1COREXP)_x000D_
_x000D_
Student services (expenses) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for admissions, registrar activities, and activities whose primary purpose is to contribute to students emotional and physical well - being and to their intellectual, cultural, and social development outside the context of the formal instructional program. Examples include student activities, cultural events, student newspapers, intramural athletics, student organizations, supplemental instruction outside the normal administration, and student records. Intercollegiate athletics and student health services may also be included except when operated as self - supporting auxiliary enterprises. Also may include information technology expenses related to student service activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources(otherwise these expenses are included in institutional support.) FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense.  _x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Institutional support expenses as a percent of total core expenses for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Institutional support expenses (F1C071) divided by total core expenses (F1COREXP)_x000D_
_x000D_
Institutional support - A functional expense category that includes expenses for the day-to-day operational support of the institution. Includes expenses for general administrative services, central executive-level activities concerned with management and long range planning, legal and fiscal operations, space management, employee personnel and records, logistical services such as purchasing and printing, and public relations and development. Also includes information technology expenses related to institutional support activities. If an institution does not separately budget and expense information technology resources, the costs associated with student services and operation and maintenance of plant will also be applied to this function. FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">All other core expenses as a percent of total core expenses for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Other core expenses is equal to the sum of expenses for the following functions:_x000D_
 _x000D_
Scholarships and fellowships expenses (F1C101) _x000D_
Other expenses and deductions (F1C141)_x000D_
_x000D_
Other core expenses is then divided by total core expenses (F1COREXP)_x000D_
_x000D_
For glossary definitions of the above finance terms see variables listed under the Finance survey.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries and wages for instruction as a percent of total expenses for instruction for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses for instruction (F1C012) divided by total expenses for instruction (F1C011)_x000D_
_x000D_
Instruction - A functional expense category that includes expenses of the colleges, schools, departments, and other instructional divisions of the institution and expenses for departmental research and public service that are not separately budgeted. Includes general academic instruction, occupational and vocational instruction, community education, preparatory and adult basic education, and regular, special, and extension sessions. Also includes expenses for both credit and non-credit activities. Excludes expenses for academic administration where the primary function is administration (e.g., academic deans). Information technology expenses related to instructional activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources are included (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support). FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits, depreciation and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries and wages for research as a percent of total expenses for research for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses for research (F1C022) divided by total expenses for research (F1C021)._x000D_
_x000D_
Research (expense) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for activities specifically organized to produce research outcomes and commissioned by an agency either external to the institution or separately budgeted by an organizational unit within the institution. The category includes institutes and research centers, and individual and project research. This function does not include nonresearch sponsored programs (e.g., training programs). Also included are information technology expenses related to research activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support.) FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation &amp; maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation &amp; maintenance of plant or interest but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits, depreciation and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries and wages for public service as a percent of total expenses for public service for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses for public service (F1C032) divided by total expenses for public service (F1C031)._x000D_
_x000D_
Public service (expense) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for activities established primarily to provide noninstructional services beneficial to individuals and groups external to the institution. Examples are conferences, institutes, general advisory service, reference bureaus, and similar services provided to particular sectors of the community. This function includes expenses for community services, cooperative extension services, and public broadcasting services. Also includes information technology expenses related to the public service activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support). FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits, depreciation and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries and wages for academic support as a percent of total expenses for academic support for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses for academic support (F1C052) divided by total expenses for academic support (F1C051)._x000D_
_x000D_
Academic support  A functional expense category that includes expenses of activities and services that support the institution's primary missions of instruction, research, and public service. It includes the retention, preservation, and display of educational materials (for example, libraries, museums, and galleries); organized activities that provide support services to the academic functions of the institution (such as a demonstration school associated with a college of education or veterinary and dental clinics if their primary purpose is to support the instructional program); media such as audiovisual services; academic administration (including academic deans but not department chairpersons); and formally organized and separately budgeted academic personnel development and course and curriculum development expenses. Also included are information technology expenses related to academic support activities; if an institution does not separately budget and expense information technology resources, the costs associated with the three primary programs will be applied to this function and the remainder to institutional support. Under FASB standards this includes actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. Under GASB standards this does not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest but may include depreciation expense._x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits, depreciation and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries and wages for student services as a percent of total expenses for student services for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses for student services (F1C062) divided by total expenses for student services (F1C061)._x000D_
_x000D_
Student services (expenses) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for admissions, registrar activities, and activities whose primary purpose is to contribute to students emotional and physical well - being and to their intellectual, cultural, and social development outside the context of the formal instructional program. Examples include student activities, cultural events, student newspapers, intramural athletics, student organizations, supplemental instruction outside the normal administration, and student records. Intercollegiate athletics and student health services may also be included except when operated as self - supporting auxiliary enterprises. Also may include information technology expenses related to student service activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources(otherwise these expenses are included in institutional support.) FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense.  _x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits, depreciation and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries and wages for institutional support as a percent of total expenses for institutional support for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses for institutional support (F1C072) divided by total expenses for institutional support (F1C071)._x000D_
_x000D_
Institutional support - A functional expense category that includes expenses for the day-to-day operational support of the institution. Includes expenses for general administrative services, central executive-level activities concerned with management and long range planning, legal and fiscal operations, space management, employee personnel and records, logistical services such as purchasing and printing, and public relations and development. Also includes information technology expenses related to institutional support activities. If an institution does not separately budget and expense information technology resources, the costs associated with student services and operation and maintenance of plant will also be applied to this function. FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits, depreciation and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries and wages for all other core expense categories as a percent of total expenses for all other core expense categories for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses for other core expense categories is equal to the sum of expenses for the following functions:_x000D_
_x000D_
Scholarships and fellowships expenses (F1C102) _x000D_
Other expenses and deductions (F1C142)_x000D_
_x000D_
and are then divided by the sum of total expenses from other core expenses categories:_x000D_
_x000D_
Scholarships and fellowships expenses (F1C101) _x000D_
Other expenses and deductions (F1C141)_x000D_
_x000D_
For glossary definitions of the above finance terms see variables listed under the Finance survey.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries and wages for core expenses as a percent of total core expenses for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Total core expenses is the sum of total expenses for the following expense functions_x000D_
_x000D_
 Instruction (F1C011)_x000D_
 Research (F1C021)_x000D_
 Public service (F1C031)_x000D_
 Academic support (F1C051) _x000D_
 Student services (F1C061)_x000D_
 Institutional support (F1C071)_x000D_
 Scholarships and fellowships expenses (F1C101) _x000D_
 Other expenses and deductions (F1C141)_x000D_
  _x000D_
 Total salaries and wages expenses is the sum of Salary and wage expenses for the following expense functions_x000D_
 _x000D_
  Instruction (F1C012)_x000D_
  Research (F1C022)_x000D_
  Public service (F1C032)_x000D_
  Academic support (F1C052) _x000D_
  Student services (F1C062)_x000D_
  Institutional support (F1C072)_x000D_
  Scholarships and fellowships expenses (F1C102) _x000D_
  Other expenses and deductions (F1C142)_x000D_
  _x000D_
Total salary and wage expenses is divided by total core expenses._x000D_
 _x000D_
For glossary definitions of the above finance terms see variables listed under the Finance survey.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Endowment assets (year end) per FTE enrollment for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Endowment assets (year end) (F1H02) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN) _x000D_
_x000D_
Endowment assets are gross investments of endowment funds, term endowment funds, and funds functioning as endowment for the institution and any of its foundations and other affiliated organizations. Endowment funds are funds whose principal is nonexpendable (true endowment) and that are intended to be invested to provide earnings for institutional use. Term endowment funds are funds which the donor has stipulated that the principal may be expended after a stated period or on the occurrence of a certain event. Funds functioning as endowment (quasi-endowment funds) are established by the governing board to function like an endowment fund but which may be totally expended at any time at the discretion of the governing board. These funds represent nonmandatory transfers from the current fund rather than a direct addition to the endowment fund, as occurs for the true endowment categories._x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries, wages, and benefit expenses as a percent of total expenses for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Total Salaries and wage expenses (F1C192) plus employee fringe benefit expenses for institutional support (F1C193) divided by total expenses  (F1C191)._x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Employee Fringe Benefits include all employee fringe benefits such as retirement plans, social security taxes, medical/dental plans, guaranteed disability income protection plans, tuition plans, housing plans, unemployment compensation plans, group life insurance plans, worker’s compensation plans, other in-kind benefits with cash options, and all other costs of employee benefits._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits, depreciation and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries and wage expenses as a percent of total expenses for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Total Salaries and wage expenses (F1C192) divided by total expenses  (F1C191)._x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Employee Fringe Benefits include all employee fringe benefits such as retirement plans, social security taxes, medical/dental plans, guaranteed disability income protection plans, tuition plans, housing plans, unemployment compensation plans, group life insurance plans, worker’s compensation plans, other in-kind benefits with cash options, and all other costs of employee benefits._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits, depreciation and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Equity ratio for public institutions using GASB 34/35 standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Total net assets (F1A18) divided by total assets (F1A06)_x000D_
_x000D_
Net assets are the excess of assets over liabilities or the residual interest in the institution's assets remaining after liabilities are deducted. The change in net assets results from revenues, gains, expenses, and losses. FASB institutions classify net assets into three categories: permanently restricted, temporarily restricted, and unrestricted. GASB institutions classify net assets into three categories: invested in capital, net of related debt; restricted (with separate displays of restricted-expendable and restricted-nonexpendable net assets); and unrestricted. Although the terms are similar, the composition of the categories of net assets between FASB and GASB institutions can differ significantly.  _x000D_
_x000D_
Total assets include current and noncurrent assets_x000D_
_x000D_
Current assets are assets that are reasonably expected to be realized in cash or sold or consumed during the next normal operating cycle (normally one year) of the institution. Liquidity or nearness to cash is not the basis for classifying assets as current or non-current; thus cash or investments intended for liquidation of liabilities due beyond the one-year period would not be current assets._x000D_
_x000D_
Noncurrent assets are assets that are not reasonably expected to be realized in cash or sold or consumed during the next normal operating cycle (normally one year) of the institution. Liquidity or nearness to cash is not the basis for determining classification as current or noncurrent. Thus cash investments intended for liquidation of liabilities due beyond the one-year period are noncurrent assets, as would assets segregated for the liquidation of long-term debts (including amounts due within the next operating cycle). Assets designated to be used to acquire, construct, or improve capital assets would be noncurrent.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Core revenues,total dollars for public and private-not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards are derived by adding revenues from the following sources:_x000D_
_x000D_
 Tuition and fees revenues (F2D01)_x000D_
 Federal appropriations (F2D02)_x000D_
 State appropriations (F2D03)_x000D_
 Local appropriations (F2D04)_x000D_
 Federal grants and contracts (F2D05)_x000D_
 State grants and contracts (F2D06)_x000D_
 Local grants and contracts (F2D07)_x000D_
 Private gifts, grants, and contracts (F2D08)_x000D_
 Contributions from affiliated entities (F2D09)_x000D_
 Investment return (F2D10)_x000D_
 Sales and services of educational activities (F2D11)_x000D_
 Other revenues (F2D15)_x000D_
 _x000D_
For glossary definitions of the above finance terms see variables listed under the Finance survey.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Tuition and fees as a percent of core revenues for public and private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Tuition and fees revenues (F2D01) divided by total core revenues (F2CORREV)_x000D_
_x000D_
Tuition and fees (revenues) (F2D01) - Revenues from all tuition and fees assessed against students (net of refunds and discounts and allowances) for educational purposes. If tuition or fees are remitted to the state as an offset to the state appropriation, the total of such tuition or fees are deducted from the total state appropriation and added to the total for tuition and fees.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Government grants and contracts as a percent of core revenues for public and private-not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Government grants and contracts is equal to the sum of Federal grants and contracts (F2D05), State grants and contracts (F2D06), and local grants and contracts (F2D07)._x000D_
_x000D_
Government grants and contract revenues is then divided by total core revenues (F2CORREV)_x000D_
_x000D_
Government grants and contracts (revenues) - Revenues from governmental agencies that are for specific research projects, other types of programs , or for general institutional operations (if not government appropriations). Examples are research projects, training programs, student financial assistance, and similar activities for which amounts are received or expenses are reimbursable under the terms of a grant or contract, including amounts to cover both direct and indirect expenses. Includes Pell Grants and reimbursement for costs of administering federal financial aid programs. Grants and contracts should be classified to identify the governmental level - federal, state, or local - funding the grant or contract to the institution; grants and contracts from other sources are classified as nongovernmental grants and contracts.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Private gifts, grants, and contracts and contributions from affiliated entities as a percent of total core revenues for public and private-not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Private gifts, grants, and contract revenues (F2D08) plus Contributions from affiliated entities (F2D09) divided by total core revenues (F2CORREV)_x000D_
_x000D_
Private gifts, grants and contracts (revenues)  Revenues from private donors for which no legal consideration is involved and from private contracts for specific goods and services provided to the funder as stipulation for receipt of the funds. Includes only those gifts, grants, and contracts that are directly related to instruction, research, public service, or other institutional purposes. Includes monies received as a result of gifts, grants, or contracts from a foreign government. Also includes the estimated dollar amount of contributed services._x000D_
_x000D_
Contributions from affiliated entities  Revenues received from non-consolidated affiliated entities, such as fund raising foundations, booster clubs, other institutionally-related foundations, and similar organizations created to support the institution or organizational components of the institution.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Investment return as a percent of core revenues for public and private-not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:. _x000D_
_x000D_
Investment return revenues (F2D10) divided by total core revenues (F2CORREV)_x000D_
_x000D_
Investment return - Income from assets including dividends, interest earnings, royalties, rent, gains (losses) etc. _x000D_
Assets - Physical items (tangible) or rights (intangible) that have value and that are owned by the institution. Assets are useful to the institution because they are a source of future services or because they can be used to secure future benefits _x000D_
Interest - The price paid (or received) for the use of money over a period of time. Interest income is one component of investment income. Interest paid by the institution is interest expense. _x000D_
Gains - Increases in the institution's net assets from peripheral or incidental transactions. This is in contrast to revenues, which occur from the institution's ongoing major or central operations. Whether a transaction generates revenue or a gain depends on the relationship of the transaction to the institution's activities. For example, the sale of computers by a college store might be part of ongoing central activities, while the sale of surplus computers from administrative offices might be considered otherwise. _x000D_
Losses - Decreases in net assets from an organization's peripheral or incidental transactions and other events affecting the organization, other than those that result from expenses</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Other core revenues as a percent of total core revenues for public or private-not-for-profit institutions using GASB 34/35 standard is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Other core revenues is equal to the sum of:_x000D_
_x000D_
Federal appropriations (F2D02)_x000D_
State appropriations (F2D03)_x000D_
Local appropriations (F2D04)_x000D_
Sales and services of educational activities (F2D11)_x000D_
Other revenues (F2D15)_x000D_
_x000D_
Other core revenues is then divided by total core revenues (F1CORREV)_x000D_
_x000D_
For glossary definitions of the above finance terms see variables listed under the Finance survey._x000D_
_x000D_
Other core revenues as a percent of total core revenues for public and private-not-for profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Revenues from tuition and fees per FTE enrollment for public and private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Tuition and fees revenues (F2D01) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
Tuition and fees (revenues) (F2D01) - Revenues from all tuition and fees assessed against students (net of refunds and discounts and allowances) for educational purposes. If tuition or fees are remitted to the state as an offset to the state appropriation, the total of such tuition or fees are deducted from the total state appropriation and added to the total for tuition and fees._x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Revenues from govenment grants and contracts per FTE enrollment for public and private-not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Government grants and contracts is equal to the sum of Federal grants and contracts (F2D05), State grants and contracts (F2D06), and local grants and contracts (F2D07)._x000D_
_x000D_
Government grants and contract revenues is then divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
Government grants and contracts (revenues) - Revenues from governmental agencies that are for specific research projects, other types of programs , or for general institutional operations (if not government appropriations). Examples are research projects, training programs, student financial assistance, and similar activities for which amounts are received or expenses are reimbursable under the terms of a grant or contract, including amounts to cover both direct and indirect expenses. Includes Pell Grants and reimbursement for costs of administering federal financial aid programs. Grants and contracts should be classified to identify the governmental level - federal, state, or local - funding the grant or contract to the institution; grants and contracts from other sources are classified as nongovernmental grants and contracts._x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Revenues from private gifts, grants, and contracts and contributions from affiliated entitiesper FTE enrollment for public and private-not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Private gifts, grants, and contract revenues (F2D08) plus Contributions from affiliated entities(F2D09) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
Private gifts, grants and contracts (revenues) Revenues from private donors for which no legal consideration is involved and from private contracts for specific goods and services provided to the funder as stipulation for receipt of the funds. Includes only those gifts, grants, and contracts that are directly related to instruction, research, public service, or other institutional purposes. Includes monies received as a result of gifts, grants, or contracts from a foreign government. Also includes the estimated dollar amount of contributed services. _x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Revenues from investment return per FTE enrollment for public and private-not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Investment return revenues (F2D10) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
Investment return - Income from assets including dividends, interest earnings, royalties, rent, gains (losses) etc. _x000D_
Assets - Physical items (tangible) or rights (intangible) that have value and that are owned by the institution. Assets are useful to the institution because they are a source of future services or because they can be used to secure future benefits _x000D_
Interest - The price paid (or received) for the use of money over a period of time. Interest income is one component of investment income. Interest paid by the institution is interest expense. _x000D_
Gains - Increases in the institution's net assets from peripheral or incidental transactions. This is in contrast to revenues, which occur from the institution's ongoing major or central operations. Whether a transaction generates revenue or a gain depends on the relationship of the transaction to the institution's activities. For example, the sale of computers by a college store might be part of ongoing central activities, while the sale of surplus computers from administrative offices might be considered otherwise. _x000D_
Losses - Decreases in net assets from an organization's peripheral or incidental transactions and other events affecting the organization, other than those that result from expenses._x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Revenues from other core revenue sources per FTE enrollment for public and private-not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows._x000D_
_x000D_
Other core revenues is equal to the sum of: _x000D_
_x000D_
Federal appropriations (F2D02)_x000D_
State appropriations (F2D03)_x000D_
Local appropriations (F2D04)_x000D_
Sales and services of educational activities (F2D11)_x000D_
Other revenues (F2D15)_x000D_
_x000D_
Other core revenues is then divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN))_x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment._x000D_
For glossary definitions of the above finance terms see variables listed under the Finance survey.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Core expenses,total dollars for public and private-not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards are derived by adding expenses for the following functions:_x000D_
 _x000D_
 Instruction (F2E011)_x000D_
 Research (F2E021)_x000D_
 Public service (F2E031)_x000D_
 Academic support (F2E041)_x000D_
 Student services (F2E051)_x000D_
 Institutional support (F2E061)_x000D_
 Net grant aid to students (F2E081) _x000D_
 Other expenses (F2E121) _x000D_
 _x000D_
For glossary definitions of the above finance terms see variables listed under the Finance survey.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Instruction expenses per FTE enrollment for public and private-not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Instruction expenses (F2E011) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
Instruction - A functional expense category that includes expenses of the colleges, schools, departments, and other instructional divisions of the institution and expenses for departmental research and public service that are not separately budgeted. Includes general academic instruction, occupational and vocational instruction, community education, preparatory and adult basic education, and regular, special, and extension sessions. Also includes expenses for both credit and non-credit activities. Excludes expenses for academic administration where the primary function is administration (e.g., academic deans). Information technology expenses related to instructional activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources are included (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support). FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense. _x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Research expenses per FTE enrollment for public and private-not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Research expenses (F2E021) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
Research (expense) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for activities specifically organized to produce research outcomes and commissioned by an agency either external to the institution or separately budgeted by an organizational unit within the institution. The category includes institutes and research centers, and individual and project research. This function does not include nonresearch sponsored programs (e.g., training programs). Also included are information technology expenses related to research activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support.) FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation &amp; maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation &amp; maintenance of plant or interest but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Public service expenses per FTE enrollment for public and private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Public service expenses (F2E031) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
Public service (expense) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for activities established primarily to provide noninstructional services beneficial to individuals and groups external to the institution. Examples are conferences, institutes, general advisory service, reference bureaus, and similar services provided to particular sectors of the community. This function includes expenses for community services, cooperative extension services, and public broadcasting services. Also includes information technology expenses related to the public service activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support). FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Academic support expenses per FTE enrollment for public and private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Academic support (F2E041) expenses divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
Academic support  A functional expense category that includes expenses of activities and services that support the institution's primary missions of instruction, research, and public service. It includes the retention, preservation, and display of educational materials (for example, libraries, museums, and galleries); organized activities that provide support services to the academic functions of the institution (such as a demonstration school associated with a college of education or veterinary and dental clinics if their primary purpose is to support the instructional program); media such as audiovisual services; academic administration (including academic deans but not department chairpersons); and formally organized and separately budgeted academic personnel development and course and curriculum development expenses. Also included are information technology expenses related to academic support activities; if an institution does not separately budget and expense information technology resources, the costs associated with the three primary programs will be applied to this function and the remainder to institutional support. Under FASB standards this includes actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. Under GASB standards this does not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest but may include depreciation expense. _x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Student services expenses per FTE enrollment for public and private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Student service expenses (F1E051) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
_x000D_
Student services (expenses) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for admissions, registrar activities, and activities whose primary purpose is to contribute to students emotional and physical well - being and to their intellectual, cultural, and social development outside the context of the formal instructional program. Examples include student activities, cultural events, student newspapers, intramural athletics, student organizations, supplemental instruction outside the normal administration, and student records. Intercollegiate athletics and student health services may also be included except when operated as self - supporting auxiliary enterprises. Also may include information technology expenses related to student service activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources(otherwise these expenses are included in institutional support.) FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense.  _x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Institutional support expenses per FTE enrollment for public and private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Institutional support expenses (F2E061) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN) _x000D_
_x000D_
Institutional support - A functional expense category that includes expenses for the day-to-day operational support of the institution. Includes expenses for general administrative services, central executive-level activities concerned with management and long range planning, legal and fiscal operations, space management, employee personnel and records, logistical services such as purchasing and printing, and public relations and development. Also includes information technology expenses related to institutional support activities. If an institution does not separately budget and expense information technology resources, the costs associated with student services and operation and maintenance of plant will also be applied to this function. FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">All other core expenses per FTE enrollment for public and private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
The sum of net grant aid to students(F2E081) and other expenses(F2E121) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12NM)_x000D_
_x000D_
Net grant aid to students (expenses)  is the portion of scholarships and fellowships granted by an institution that exceeds the amount applied to institutional charges such as tuition and fees or room and board. The amount reported as expense excludes allowances. _x000D_
_x000D_
Other expenses (F2E121) is a generated expense category on the finance component that is an expense that cannot be included in the core expense functions (instruction, research, public service, academic support, student services, institutional support and net grant aid to students) or the noncore expense functions(auxilary enterprises, hospitals and independant operations)_x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment._x000D_
For glossary definitions of the above finance terms see variables listed under the Finance survey.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Instruction expenses as a percent of total core expenses for public and private-not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Instruction expenses (F2E011) divided by total core expenses (F2COREXP)_x000D_
_x000D_
Instruction - A functional expense category that includes expenses of the colleges, schools, departments, and other instructional divisions of the institution and expenses for departmental research and public service that are not separately budgeted. Includes general academic instruction, occupational and vocational instruction, community education, preparatory and adult basic education, and regular, special, and extension sessions. Also includes expenses for both credit and non-credit activities. Excludes expenses for academic administration where the primary function is administration (e.g., academic deans). Information technology expenses related to instructional activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources are included (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support). FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Research expenses as a percent of total core expenses for public and private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Research expenses (F2E021) divided by total core expenses (F2COREXP)_x000D_
_x000D_
Research (expense) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for activities specifically organized to produce research outcomes and commissioned by an agency either external to the institution or separately budgeted by an organizational unit within the institution. The category includes institutes and research centers, and individual and project research. This function does not include nonresearch sponsored programs (e.g., training programs). Also included are information technology expenses related to research activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support.) FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation &amp; maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation &amp; maintenance of plant or interest but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Public service expenses as a percent of total core expenses  for public and private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Public service expenses (F2E031) divided by total core expenses (F2COREXP)_x000D_
_x000D_
Public service (expense) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for activities established primarily to provide noninstructional services beneficial to individuals and groups external to the institution. Examples are conferences, institutes, general advisory service, reference bureaus, and similar services provided to particular sectors of the community. This function includes expenses for community services, cooperative extension services, and public broadcasting services. Also includes information technology expenses related to the public service activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support). FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Academic support expenses as a percent of total core expenses for public and private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Academic support (F2E041) expenses divided by total core expenses (F2COREXP)_x000D_
_x000D_
Academic support  A functional expense category that includes expenses of activities and services that support the institution's primary missions of instruction, research, and public service. It includes the retention, preservation, and display of educational materials (for example, libraries, museums, and galleries); organized activities that provide support services to the academic functions of the institution (such as a demonstration school associated with a college of education or veterinary and dental clinics if their primary purpose is to support the instructional program); media such as audiovisual services; academic administration (including academic deans but not department chairpersons); and formally organized and separately budgeted academic personnel development and course and curriculum development expenses. Also included are information technology expenses related to academic support activities; if an institution does not separately budget and expense information technology resources, the costs associated with the three primary programs will be applied to this function and the remainder to institutional support. Under FASB standards this includes actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. Under GASB standards this does not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest but may include depreciation expense.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Student services expenses as a percent for public and private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Student service expenses (F1E051) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (F2COREXP))_x000D_
_x000D_
Student services (expenses) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for admissions, registrar activities, and activities whose primary purpose is to contribute to students emotional and physical well - being and to their intellectual, cultural, and social development outside the context of the formal instructional program. Examples include student activities, cultural events, student newspapers, intramural athletics, student organizations, supplemental instruction outside the normal administration, and student records. Intercollegiate athletics and student health services may also be included except when operated as self - supporting auxiliary enterprises. Also may include information technology expenses related to student service activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources(otherwise these expenses are included in institutional support.) FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Institutional support expenses as a percent of total core expenses for public and private not-for-profit  institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Institutional support expenses (F2E061) divided by total core expenses (F2COREXP)_x000D_
_x000D_
Institutional support - A functional expense category that includes expenses for the day-to-day operational support of the institution. Includes expenses for general administrative services, central executive-level activities concerned with management and long range planning, legal and fiscal operations, space management, employee personnel and records, logistical services such as purchasing and printing, and public relations and development. Also includes information technology expenses related to institutional support activities. If an institution does not separately budget and expense information technology resources, the costs associated with student services and operation and maintenance of plant will also be applied to this function. FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">All other core expenses as a percent of total core expenses for public and private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
 _x000D_
The sum of net grant aid to students(F2E081) and other expenses(F2E121) divided by total core expenses (F2COREXP)_x000D_
_x000D_
Net grant aid to students (expenses)  is the portion of scholarships and fellowships granted by an institution that exceeds the amount applied to institutional charges such as tuition and fees or room and board. The amount reported as expense excludes allowances. _x000D_
_x000D_
Other expenses (F2E121) is a generated expense category on the finance component that is an expense that cannot be included in the core expense functions (instruction, research, public service, academic support, student services, institutional support and net grant aid to students) or the noncore expense functions(auxilary enterprises, hospitals and independant operations).</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries and wages for instruction as a percent of total expenses for instruction for public and private not-for-profit-institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses for instruction (F2E012) divided by total expenses for instruction (F2E011)_x000D_
_x000D_
Instruction - A functional expense category that includes expenses of the colleges, schools, departments, and other instructional divisions of the institution and expenses for departmental research and public service that are not separately budgeted. Includes general academic instruction, occupational and vocational instruction, community education, preparatory and adult basic education, and regular, special, and extension sessions. Also includes expenses for both credit and non-credit activities. Excludes expenses for academic administration where the primary function is administration (e.g., academic deans). Information technology expenses related to instructional activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources are included (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support). FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits,operations of plant, depreciation, interest and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries and wages for research as a percent of total expenses for research for public and private not-for-profit-institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses for research (F2E022) divided by total expenses for research (F2E021)._x000D_
_x000D_
Research (expense) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for activities specifically organized to produce research outcomes and commissioned by an agency either external to the institution or separately budgeted by an organizational unit within the institution. The category includes institutes and research centers, and individual and project research. This function does not include nonresearch sponsored programs (e.g., training programs). Also included are information technology expenses related to research activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support.) FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation &amp; maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation &amp; maintenance of plant or interest but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits,operations of plant, depreciation, interest and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries and wages for public service as a percent of total expenses for public service for public private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses for public service (F2E032) divided by total expenses for public service (F2E031)._x000D_
_x000D_
Public service (expense) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for activities established primarily to provide noninstructional services beneficial to individuals and groups external to the institution. Examples are conferences, institutes, general advisory service, reference bureaus, and similar services provided to particular sectors of the community. This function includes expenses for community services, cooperative extension services, and public broadcasting services. Also includes information technology expenses related to the public service activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support). FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits,operations of plant, depreciation, interest and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries and wages for academic support as a percent of total expenses for academic support for public and private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses for academic support (F2E042) divided by total expenses for academic support (F2E041)._x000D_
_x000D_
Academic support  A functional expense category that includes expenses of activities and services that support the institution's primary missions of instruction, research, and public service. It includes the retention, preservation, and display of educational materials (for example, libraries, museums, and galleries); organized activities that provide support services to the academic functions of the institution (such as a demonstration school associated with a college of education or veterinary and dental clinics if their primary purpose is to support the instructional program); media such as audiovisual services; academic administration (including academic deans but not department chairpersons); and formally organized and separately budgeted academic personnel development and course and curriculum development expenses. Also included are information technology expenses related to academic support activities; if an institution does not separately budget and expense information technology resources, the costs associated with the three primary programs will be applied to this function and the remainder to institutional support. Under FASB standards this includes actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. Under GASB standards this does not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest but may include depreciation expense._x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits,operations of plant, depreciation, interest and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries and wages for student services as a percent of total expenses for student services for public and private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses for student services (F2E052) divided by total expenses for student services (F2E051)._x000D_
_x000D_
Student services (expenses) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for admissions, registrar activities, and activities whose primary purpose is to contribute to students emotional and physical well - being and to their intellectual, cultural, and social development outside the context of the formal instructional program. Examples include student activities, cultural events, student newspapers, intramural athletics, student organizations, supplemental instruction outside the normal administration, and student records. Intercollegiate athletics and student health services may also be included except when operated as self - supporting auxiliary enterprises. Also may include information technology expenses related to student service activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources(otherwise these expenses are included in institutional support.) FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense.  _x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits,operations of plant, depreciation, interest and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries and wages for institutional support as a percent of total expenses for institutional support for public and private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses for institutional support (F2E062) divided by total expenses for institutional support (F2E061)._x000D_
_x000D_
Institutional support - A functional expense category that includes expenses for the day-to-day operational support of the institution. Includes expenses for general administrative services, central executive-level activities concerned with management and long range planning, legal and fiscal operations, space management, employee personnel and records, logistical services such as purchasing and printing, and public relations and development. Also includes information technology expenses related to institutional support activities. If an institution does not separately budget and expense information technology resources, the costs associated with student services and operation and maintenance of plant will also be applied to this function. FASB institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits,operations of plant, depreciation, interest and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries and wages for other core expense functions as a percent of total expenses for other core expense functions for public and private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
 _x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses (F2E082) for net grant aid to students,  are added to salaries and wage expenses (F2E122) for other expense functions.  The sum is then divided total other core expenses which is the sum of total expenses for net grant aid to students (F2E081) and other expenses (F2E121)._x000D_
Net grant aid to students (expenses)  is the portion of scholarships and fellowships granted by an institution that exceeds the amount applied to institutional charges such as tuition and fees or room and board. The amount reported as expense excludes allowances. _x000D_
_x000D_
Other expenses (F2E121) is a generated expense category on the finance component that is an expense that cannot be included in the core expense functions (instruction, research, public service, academic support, student services, institutional support and net grant aid to students) or the noncore expense functions(auxilary enterprises, hospitals and independant operations).</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries and wages for core expenses as a percent of total core expenses for public and private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Total core expenses is the sum of total expenses for the following expense functions_x000D_
 _x000D_
 Instruction (F2E011)_x000D_
 Research (F2E021)_x000D_
 Public service (F2E031)_x000D_
 Academic support (F2E041)_x000D_
 Student services (F2E051)_x000D_
 Institutional support (F2E061)_x000D_
 Net grant aid to students (F2E081) _x000D_
 Other expenses (F2E121) _x000D_
 _x000D_
Total salaries and wage expenses is the sum of total expenses for the following expense functions_x000D_
  _x000D_
 Instruction (F2E012)_x000D_
 Research (F2E022)_x000D_
 Public service (F2E032)_x000D_
 Academic support (F2E042)_x000D_
 Student services (F2E052)_x000D_
 Institutional support (F2E062)_x000D_
 Net grant aid to students (F2E082) _x000D_
 Other expenses (F2E122) _x000D_
 _x000D_
Total salary and wage expense divided by total core expenses._x000D_
 _x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits,operations of plant, depreciation, interest and other expenses. _x000D_
For glossary definitions of the above finance terms see variables listed under the Finance survey.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Endowment assets (year end) per FTE enrollment for public and private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Endowment assets (year end) (F2H02) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN) _x000D_
_x000D_
Endowment assets are gross investments of endowment funds, term endowment funds, and funds functioning as endowment for the institution and any of its foundations and other affiliated organizations. Endowment funds are funds whose principal is nonexpendable (true endowment) and that are intended to be invested to provide earnings for institutional use. Term endowment funds are funds which the donor has stipulated that the principal may be expended after a stated period or on the occurrence of a certain event. Funds functioning as endowment (quasi-endowment funds) are established by the governing board to function like an endowment fund but which may be totally expended at any time at the discretion of the governing board. These funds represent nonmandatory transfers from the current fund rather than a direct addition to the endowment fund, as occurs for the true endowment categories._x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
_x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries, wages, and benefit expenses as a percent of total expenses for public and private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Total Salaries and wage expenses (F2E132) plus employee fringe benefit expenses for institutional support (F2E133) divided by total expenses  (F2E131)._x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Employee Fringe Benefits include all employee fringe benefits such as retirement plans, social security taxes, medical/dental plans, guaranteed disability income protection plans, tuition plans, housing plans, unemployment compensation plans, group life insurance plans, worker’s compensation plans, other in-kind benefits with cash options, and all other costs of employee benefits._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits,operations of plant, depreciation, interest and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries and wage expenses as a percent of total expenses for public and private not-for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Total Salaries and wage expenses (F2E132) divided by total expenses (F2E131)._x000D_
_x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Employee Fringe Benefits include all employee fringe benefits such as retirement plans, social security taxes, medical/dental plans, guaranteed disability income protection plans, tuition plans, housing plans, unemployment compensation plans, group life insurance plans, worker’s compensation plans, other in-kind benefits with cash options, and all other costs of employee benefits._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits,operations of plant, depreciation, interest and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Equity ratio for public and private-not-for profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
_x000D_
Total net assets (F2A06) divided by total assets (F2A02)_x000D_
_x000D_
Net assets are the excess of assets over liabilities or the residual interest in the institution's assets remaining after liabilities are deducted. The change in net assets results from revenues, gains, expenses, and losses. FASB institutions classify net assets into three categories: permanently restricted, temporarily restricted, and unrestricted. GASB institutions classify net assets into three categories: invested in capital, net of related debt; restricted (with separate displays of restricted-expendable and restricted-nonexpendable net assets); and unrestricted. Although the terms are similar, the composition of the categories of net assets between FASB and GASB institutions can differ significantly. _x000D_
_x000D_
Total assets include  _x000D_
a) Cash, cash equivalents, and temporary investments;_x000D_
b) Receivables (net of allowance for uncollectible amounts); _x000D_
c) Inventories, prepaid expenses, and deferred charges; _x000D_
d) Amounts held by trustees for construction and debt service; _x000D_
e) Long-term investments; _x000D_
f) Plant, property, and equipment; and, _x000D_
g) Other assets</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Core revenues,total dollars for private for-profit institutions are derived by adding revenues from the following sources:_x000D_
 Tuition and fees revenues (F3D01)_x000D_
 Federal appropriations, grants and contracts (F3D02)_x000D_
 State and local appropriations, grants and contracts (F3D03)_x000D_
 Private gifts, grants, and contracts (F3D04)_x000D_
 Investment income and investment gains (losses) included in net income (F3D05)_x000D_
 Sales and services of educational activities (F3D06)_x000D_
Other revenues (F3D08)_x000D_
For glossary definitions of the above finance terms see variables listed under the Finance survey.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Tuition and fees as a percent of core revenues for private for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Tuition and fees revenues (F3D01) divided by total core revenues (F3CORREV)_x000D_
Tuition and fees (revenues) (F3D01) - Revenues from all tuition and fees assessed against students (net of refunds and discounts and allowances) for educational purposes. If tuition or fees are remitted to the state as an offset to the state appropriation, the total of such tuition or fees are deducted from the total state appropriation and added to the total for tuition and fees.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Government grants and contracts as a percent of core revenues private for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Government grants and contracts is equal to the sum of Federal grants and contracts (F3D02B), State grants and contracts (F3D03B), and local grants and contracts (F3D03D)._x000D_
Government grants and contract revenues is then divided by total core revenues (F3CORREV)_x000D_
Government grants and contracts (revenues) - Revenues from governmental agencies that are for specific research projects, other types of programs , or for general institutional operations (if not government appropriations). Examples are research projects, training programs, student financial assistance, and similar activities for which amounts are received or expenses are reimbursable under the terms of a grant or contract, including amounts to cover both direct and indirect expenses. Includes Pell Grants and reimbursement for costs of administering federal financial aid programs. Grants and contracts should be classified to identify the governmental level - federal, state, or local - funding the grant or contract to the institution; grants and contracts from other sources are classified as nongovernmental grants and contracts.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Private gifts, grants, and contracts as a percent of total core revenues for private for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Private gifts, grants, and contract revenues (F3D04) plus Contributions from affiliated entities (F3D09) divided by total core revenues (F3CORREV)_x000D_
Private gifts, grants and contracts (revenues)  Revenues from private donors for which no legal consideration is involved and from private contracts for specific goods and services provided to the funder as stipulation for receipt of the funds. Includes only those gifts, grants, and contracts that are directly related to instruction, research, public service, or other institutional purposes. Includes monies received as a result of gifts, grants, or contracts from a foreign government. Also includes the estimated dollar amount of contributed services._x000D_
Contributions from affiliated entities  Revenues received from non-consolidated affiliated entities, such as fund raising foundations, booster clubs, other institutionally-related foundations, and similar organizations created to support the institution or organizational components of the institution.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Investment return as a percent of core revenues for private for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Investment return revenues (F3D05) divided by total core revenues (F3CORREV)_x000D_
Investment return - Income from assets including dividends, interest earnings, royalties, rent, gains (losses) etc. _x000D_
Assets - Physical items (tangible) or rights (intangible) that have value and that are owned by the institution. Assets are useful to the institution because they are a source of future services or because they can be used to secure future benefits _x000D_
Interest - The price paid (or received) for the use of money over a period of time. Interest income is one component of investment income. Interest paid by the institution is interest expense. _x000D_
Gains - Increases in the institution's net assets from peripheral or incidental transactions. This is in contrast to revenues, which occur from the institution's ongoing major or central operations. Whether a transaction generates revenue or a gain depends on the relationship of the transaction to the institution's activities. For example, the sale of computers by a college store might be part of ongoing central activities, while the sale of surplus computers from administrative offices might be considered otherwise. _x000D_
Losses - Decreases in net assets from an organization's peripheral or incidental transactions and other events affecting the organization, other than those that result from expenses</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Sales and services of educational activities as a percent of core revenues for private-for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Sales and services of educational activities (F3D06) divided by total core revenues (F3CORREV)_x000D_
Sales and services of educational activities (revenues) are revenues from the sales of goods or services that are incidental to the conduct of instruction, research or public service. Examples include film rentals, sales of scientific and literary publications, testing services, university presses, dairy products, machine shop products, data processing services, cosmetology services, and sales of handcrafts prepared in classes</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Other core revenues as a percent of total core revenues for private for-profit institutions using FASB standards is derived as follows: _x000D_
_x000D_
Other core revenues is the sum of Federal (F3D02A). state (F3D03A) and local (F3D03C) appropriations and Other revenues (F3D08). Other core revenues is then divided by total core revenues F3CORREV._x000D_
_x000D_
Prior to Fiscal year 2014, Other core revenues included Private gifts, grants, and contracts (F3D04) and Investment income and investment gains (losses) included in net income (F3D05) and Other revenues (F3D08). Appropriations from federal, state and local sources were combined with government grants and contracts from federal, state and local sources into a category called Government appropriations, grants, and contracts._x000D_
</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Revenues from tuition and fees per FTE enrollment for private for-profit institutions_x000D_
Tuition and fees revenues (F3D01) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
Tuition and fees (revenues) (F3D01) - Revenues from all tuition and fees assessed against students (net of refunds and discounts and allowances) for educational purposes. If tuition or fees are remitted to the state as an offset to the state appropriation, the total of such tuition or fees are deducted from the total state appropriation and added to the total for tuition and fees._x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Revenues from govenment grants and contracts per FTE enrollment for private for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Government grants and contracts is equal to the sum of Federal grants and contracts (F3D02B), State grants and contracts (F3D03B), and local grants and contracts (F3D03D)._x000D_
Government grants and contract revenues is then divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
Government grants and contracts (revenues) - Revenues from governmental agencies that are for specific research projects, other types of programs , or for general institutional operations (if not government appropriations). Examples are research projects, training programs, student financial assistance, and similar activities for which amounts are received or expenses are reimbursable under the terms of a grant or contract, including amounts to cover both direct and indirect expenses. Includes Pell Grants and reimbursement for costs of administering federal financial aid programs. Grants and contracts should be classified to identify the governmental level - federal, state, or local - funding the grant or contract to the institution; grants and contracts from other sources are classified as nongovernmental grants and contracts.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Revenues from private gifts, grants, and contracts  per FTE enrollment for private for-profit institutions  is derived as follows:_x000D_
Private gifts, grants, and contract revenues (F3D04)  divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
Private gifts, grants and contracts (revenues) Revenues from private donors for which no legal consideration is involved and from private contracts for specific goods and services provided to the funder as stipulation for receipt of the funds. Includes only those gifts, grants, and contracts that are directly related to instruction, research, public service, or other institutional purposes. Includes monies received as a result of gifts, grants, or contracts from a foreign government. Also includes the estimated dollar amount of contributed services. _x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Revenues from investment return per FTE enrollment for private for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Investment return revenues (F3D05) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
Investment return - Income from assets including dividends, interest earnings, royalties, rent, gains (losses) etc. _x000D_
Assets - Physical items (tangible) or rights (intangible) that have value and that are owned by the institution. Assets are useful to the institution because they are a source of future services or because they can be used to secure future benefits _x000D_
Interest - The price paid (or received) for the use of money over a period of time. Interest income is one component of investment income. Interest paid by the institution is interest expense. _x000D_
Gains - Increases in the institution's net assets from peripheral or incidental transactions. This is in contrast to revenues, which occur from the institution's ongoing major or central operations. Whether a transaction generates revenue or a gain depends on the relationship of the transaction to the institution's activities. For example, the sale of computers by a college store might be part of ongoing central activities, while the sale of surplus computers from administrative offices might be considered otherwise. _x000D_
Losses - Decreases in net assets from an organization's peripheral or incidental transactions and other events affecting the organization, other than those that result from expenses._x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Revenues from sales and services of educational activities per FTE enrollment for private for-profit institutions using Private for-profit standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
Revenues from sales and services of educational activities (F3D06) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
Sales and services of educational activities (revenues) are revenues from the sales of goods or services that are incidental to the conduct of instruction, research or public service. Examples include film rentals, sales of scientific and literary publications, testing services, university presses, dairy products, machine shop products, data processing services, cosmetology services, and sales of handcrafts prepared in classes _x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Revenues from other core revenue sources per FTE enrollment for private-for-profit institutions using Private for-profit standards is derived as follows. _x000D_
_x000D_
Other core revenues is equal to the sum of: Federal (F3D02A). state (F3D03A) and local (F3D03C) appopriations and Other revenues (F3D08)_x000D_
_x000D_
Other core revenues is then divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN) _x000D_
_x000D_
Prior to Fiscal year 2014, Other core revenues included Private gifts, grants, and contracts (F3D04) and Investment income and investment gains (losses) included in net income (F3D05) and Other revenues (F3D08). Appropriations from federal, state and local sources were combined with government grants and contracts from federal, state and local sources into a category called Government appropriations, grants, and contracts_x000D_
_x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours). For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment. For glossary definitions of the above finance terms see variables listed under the Finance survey.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Core expenses,total dollars for private for-profit institutions are derived by adding expenses for the following functions:_x000D_
 Instruction (F3E011)_x000D_
 Research (F3E02A1)  and public service (F3E02B1)_x000D_
 Academic (F3E03A1)  and institutional (F3E03C1) support, and student services (F3E03B1)_x000D_
 Net grant aid to students (F3E051)_x000D_
 All other expenses (F3E06)_x000D_
For glossary definitions of the above finance terms see variables listed under the Finance survey.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Instruction expenses per FTE enrollment for private forprofit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Instruction expenses (F3E011) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
Instruction - A functional expense category that includes expenses of the colleges, schools, departments, and other instructional divisions of the institution and expenses for departmental research and public service that are not separately budgeted. Includes general academic instruction, occupational and vocational instruction, community education, preparatory and adult basic education, and regular, special, and extension sessions. Also includes expenses for both credit and non-credit activities. Excludes expenses for academic administration where the primary function is administration (e.g., academic deans). Information technology expenses related to instructional activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources are included (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support). Private for-profit institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense. _x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Research expenses per FTE enrollment for private for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Research expenses (F3E02A1) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
Research (expense) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for activities specifically organized to produce research outcomes and commissioned by an agency either external to the institution or separately budgeted by an organizational unit within the institution. The category includes institutes and research centers, and individual and project research. This function does not include nonresearch sponsored programs (e.g., training programs). Also included are information technology expenses related to research activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support.) Private for-profit institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation &amp; maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation &amp; maintenance of plant or interest but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Public service expenses per FTE enrollment for private for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Public service expenses (F3E02B1) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
Public service (expense) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for activities established primarily to provide noninstructional services beneficial to individuals and groups external to the institution. Examples are conferences, institutes, general advisory service, reference bureaus, and similar services provided to particular sectors of the community. This function includes expenses for community services, cooperative extension services, and public broadcasting services. Also includes information technology expenses related to the public service activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support). Private for-profit institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Academic support expenses per FTE enrollment for  private for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Academic support (F3E03A1) expenses divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
Academic support  A functional expense category that includes expenses of activities and services that support the institution's primary missions of instruction, research, and public service. It includes the retention, preservation, and display of educational materials (for example, libraries, museums, and galleries); organized activities that provide support services to the academic functions of the institution (such as a demonstration school associated with a college of education or veterinary and dental clinics if their primary purpose is to support the instructional program); media such as audiovisual services; academic administration (including academic deans but not department chairpersons); and formally organized and separately budgeted academic personnel development and course and curriculum development expenses. Also included are information technology expenses related to academic support activities; if an institution does not separately budget and expense information technology resources, the costs associated with the three primary programs will be applied to this function and the remainder to institutional support. Under Private for-profit standards this includes actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. Under GASB standards this does not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest but may include depreciation expense. _x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Student services expenses per FTE enrollment for private for-profit institutions using is derived as follows:_x000D_
Student service expenses (F3E03B1) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
Student services (expenses) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for admissions, registrar activities, and activities whose primary purpose is to contribute to students emotional and physical well - being and to their intellectual, cultural, and social development outside the context of the formal instructional program. Examples include student activities, cultural events, student newspapers, intramural athletics, student organizations, supplemental instruction outside the normal administration, and student records. Intercollegiate athletics and student health services may also be included except when operated as self - supporting auxiliary enterprises. Also may include information technology expenses related to student service activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources(otherwise these expenses are included in institutional support.) Private for-profit institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense.  _x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Institutional support expenses per FTE enrollment for private for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Institutional support expenses (F3E03C1) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN) _x000D_
Institutional support - A functional expense category that includes expenses for the day-to-day operational support of the institution. Includes expenses for general administrative services, central executive-level activities concerned with management and long range planning, legal and fiscal operations, space management, employee personnel and records, logistical services such as purchasing and printing, and public relations and development. Also includes information technology expenses related to institutional support activities. If an institution does not separately budget and expense information technology resources, the costs associated with student services and operation and maintenance of plant will also be applied to this function. Private for-profit institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">All other core expenses per FTE enrollment for private for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
The sum of net grant aid to students (F3E051) and other expenses(F3E061) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (FTE12MN)_x000D_
Net grant aid to students (expenses)  is the portion of scholarships and fellowships granted by an institution that exceeds the amount applied to institutional charges such as tuition and fees or room and board. The amount reported as expense excludes allowances. _x000D_
Other expenses (F3E061) is a generated expense category on the finance component that is an expense that cannot be included in the core expense functions (instruction, research, public service, academic support, student services, institutional support and net grant aid to students) or noncore expense function(auxilary enterprises)._x000D_
The full-time-equivalent (FTE) enrollment used is the sum of the institutions’ FTE undergraduate enrollment and FTE graduate enrollment (as calculated from or reported on the 12-month Enrollment component) plus the estimated FTE of first-professional students. Undergraduate and graduate FTE are estimated using 12-month instructional activity (credit and/or clock hours)._x000D_
For more information see the variable description for 12-month full-time equivalent enrollment (info link) under frequently used\ 12-month enrollment.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Instruction expenses as a percent of total core expenses for private-for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Instruction expenses (F3E011) divided by total core expenses (F3COREXP)_x000D_
Instruction - A functional expense category that includes expenses of the colleges, schools, departments, and other instructional divisions of the institution and expenses for departmental research and public service that are not separately budgeted. Includes general academic instruction, occupational and vocational instruction, community education, preparatory and adult basic education, and regular, special, and extension sessions. Also includes expenses for both credit and non-credit activities. Excludes expenses for academic administration where the primary function is administration (e.g., academic deans). Information technology expenses related to instructional activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources are included (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support). Private for-profit institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Research expenses as a percent of total core expenses for private for-profit institutions  is derived as follows:_x000D_
Research expenses (F3E02A1) divided by total core expenses (F3COREXP)_x000D_
Research (expense) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for activities specifically organized to produce research outcomes and commissioned by an agency either external to the institution or separately budgeted by an organizational unit within the institution. The category includes institutes and research centers, and individual and project research. This function does not include nonresearch sponsored programs (e.g., training programs). Also included are information technology expenses related to research activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support.) Private for-profit institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation &amp; maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation &amp; maintenance of plant or interest but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Public service expenses as a percent of total core expenses  private for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Public service expenses (F3E02B1) divided by total core expenses (F3COREXP)_x000D_
Public service (expense) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for activities established primarily to provide noninstructional services beneficial to individuals and groups external to the institution. Examples are conferences, institutes, general advisory service, reference bureaus, and similar services provided to particular sectors of the community. This function includes expenses for community services, cooperative extension services, and public broadcasting services. Also includes information technology expenses related to the public service activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support). Private for-profit institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Academic support expenses as a percent of total core expenses for private for-profit institutionss is derived as follows:_x000D_
Academic support (F3E03A1) expenses divided by total core expenses (F3COREXP)_x000D_
Academic support  A functional expense category that includes expenses of activities and services that support the institution's primary missions of instruction, research, and public service. It includes the retention, preservation, and display of educational materials (for example, libraries, museums, and galleries); organized activities that provide support services to the academic functions of the institution (such as a demonstration school associated with a college of education or veterinary and dental clinics if their primary purpose is to support the instructional program); media such as audiovisual services; academic administration (including academic deans but not department chairpersons); and formally organized and separately budgeted academic personnel development and course and curriculum development expenses. Also included are information technology expenses related to academic support activities; if an institution does not separately budget and expense information technology resources, the costs associated with the three primary programs will be applied to this function and the remainder to institutional support. Under Private for-profit standards this includes actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. Under GASB standards this does not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest but may include depreciation expense.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Student services expenses as a percent for private for-profit institutions using  is derived as follows:_x000D_
Student service expenses (F1E03B1) divided by 12-month FTE enrollment (F3COREXP))_x000D_
Student services (expenses) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for admissions, registrar activities, and activities whose primary purpose is to contribute to students emotional and physical well - being and to their intellectual, cultural, and social development outside the context of the formal instructional program. Examples include student activities, cultural events, student newspapers, intramural athletics, student organizations, supplemental instruction outside the normal administration, and student records. Intercollegiate athletics and student health services may also be included except when operated as self - supporting auxiliary enterprises. Also may include information technology expenses related to student service activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources(otherwise these expenses are included in institutional support.) Private for-profit institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Institutional support expenses as a percent of total core expenses for private for-profit  institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Institutional support expenses (F3E03C1) divided by total core expenses (F3COREXP)_x000D_
Institutional support - A functional expense category that includes expenses for the day-to-day operational support of the institution. Includes expenses for general administrative services, central executive-level activities concerned with management and long range planning, legal and fiscal operations, space management, employee personnel and records, logistical services such as purchasing and printing, and public relations and development. Also includes information technology expenses related to institutional support activities. If an institution does not separately budget and expense information technology resources, the costs associated with student services and operation and maintenance of plant will also be applied to this function. Private for-profit institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">All other core expenses as a percent of total core expenses for private for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
 The sum of net grant aid to students (F3E051) and other expenses(F3E061) divided by total core expenses (F3COREXP)_x000D_
Net grant aid to students (expenses)  is the portion of scholarships and fellowships granted by an institution that exceeds the amount applied to institutional charges such as tuition and fees or room and board. The amount reported as expense excludes allowances. _x000D_
Other expenses (F3E061) is a generated expense category on the finance component that is an expense that cannot be included in the core expense functions (instruction, research, public service, academic support, student services, institutional support and net grant aid to students) or the noncore expense functions(auxilary enterprises, hospitals and independant operations).</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries, wages, and benefit expenses for instruction as a percent of total expenses for instruction for private for-profit-institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses for instruction (F3E012) divided by total expenses for instruction (F3E011)_x000D_
Instruction - A functional expense category that includes expenses of the colleges, schools, departments, and other instructional divisions of the institution and expenses for departmental research and public service that are not separately budgeted. Includes general academic instruction, occupational and vocational instruction, community education, preparatory and adult basic education, and regular, special, and extension sessions. Also includes expenses for both credit and non-credit activities. Excludes expenses for academic administration where the primary function is administration (e.g., academic deans). Information technology expenses related to instructional activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources are included (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support). Private for-profit institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits,operations of plant, depreciation, interest and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries, wages, and benefit expenses for research as a percent of total expenses for research for private for-profit-institutions using Private for-profit standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses for research (F3E02A2) divided by total expenses for research (F3E02A1)._x000D_
Research (expense) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for activities specifically organized to produce research outcomes and commissioned by an agency either external to the institution or separately budgeted by an organizational unit within the institution. The category includes institutes and research centers, and individual and project research. This function does not include nonresearch sponsored programs (e.g., training programs). Also included are information technology expenses related to research activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support.) Private for-profit institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation &amp; maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation &amp; maintenance of plant or interest but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits,operations of plant, depreciation, interest and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries, wages, and benefit expenses for public service as a percent of total expenses for public service for private for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses for public service (F3E02B2) divided by total expenses for public service (F3E02B1)._x000D_
Public service (expense) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for activities established primarily to provide noninstructional services beneficial to individuals and groups external to the institution. Examples are conferences, institutes, general advisory service, reference bureaus, and similar services provided to particular sectors of the community. This function includes expenses for community services, cooperative extension services, and public broadcasting services. Also includes information technology expenses related to the public service activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources (otherwise these expenses are included in academic support). Private for-profit institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits,operations of plant, depreciation, interest and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries, wages, and benefit expenses for academic support as a percent of total expenses for academic support for private for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses for academic support (F3E03A2) divided by total expenses for academic support (F3E03A1)._x000D_
Academic support  A functional expense category that includes expenses of activities and services that support the institution's primary missions of instruction, research, and public service. It includes the retention, preservation, and display of educational materials (for example, libraries, museums, and galleries); organized activities that provide support services to the academic functions of the institution (such as a demonstration school associated with a college of education or veterinary and dental clinics if their primary purpose is to support the instructional program); media such as audiovisual services; academic administration (including academic deans but not department chairpersons); and formally organized and separately budgeted academic personnel development and course and curriculum development expenses. Also included are information technology expenses related to academic support activities; if an institution does not separately budget and expense information technology resources, the costs associated with the three primary programs will be applied to this function and the remainder to institutional support. Under Private for-profit standards this includes actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. Under GASB standards this does not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest but may include depreciation expense._x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits,operations of plant, depreciation, interest and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries, wages, and benefit expenses for student services as a percent of total expenses for student services for private not-for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses for student services (F3E03B2) divided by total expenses for student services (F3E03B1)._x000D_
Student services (expenses) - A functional expense category that includes expenses for admissions, registrar activities, and activities whose primary purpose is to contribute to students emotional and physical well - being and to their intellectual, cultural, and social development outside the context of the formal instructional program. Examples include student activities, cultural events, student newspapers, intramural athletics, student organizations, supplemental instruction outside the normal administration, and student records. Intercollegiate athletics and student health services may also be included except when operated as self - supporting auxiliary enterprises. Also may include information technology expenses related to student service activities if the institution separately budgets and expenses information technology resources(otherwise these expenses are included in institutional support.) Private for-profit institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest, and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense.  _x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits,operations of plant, depreciation, interest and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries, wages, and benefit expenses for institutional support as a percent of total expenses for institutional support for private for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses for institutional support (F3E03C2) divided by total expenses for institutional support (F3E03C1)._x000D_
Institutional support - A functional expense category that includes expenses for the day-to-day operational support of the institution. Includes expenses for general administrative services, central executive-level activities concerned with management and long range planning, legal and fiscal operations, space management, employee personnel and records, logistical services such as purchasing and printing, and public relations and development. Also includes information technology expenses related to institutional support activities. If an institution does not separately budget and expense information technology resources, the costs associated with student services and operation and maintenance of plant will also be applied to this function. Private for-profit institutions include actual or allocated costs for operation and maintenance of plant, interest and depreciation. GASB institutions do not include operation and maintenance of plant or interest, but may, as an option, distribute depreciation expense._x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
_x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits,operations of plant, depreciation, interest and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries, wages, and benefit expenses for other core expense functions  as a percent of total expenses for other core expense functions for private for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Salaries and wage expenses (F3E062) divided by total other core expenses which is the sum of total expenses for net grant aid to students (F3E051) and other expenses (F3E061)._x000D_
Net grant aid to students (expenses)  is the portion of scholarships and fellowships granted by an institution that exceeds the amount applied to institutional charges such as tuition and fees or room and board. The amount reported as expense excludes allowances. _x000D_
Other expenses (F3E061) is a generated expense category on the finance component that is an expense that cannot be included in the core expense functions (instruction, research, public service, academic support, student services, institutional support and net grant aid to students) or the noncore expense functions(auxilary enterprises, hospitals and independant operations).</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries and wages for core expenses as a percent of total core expenses for private for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Total core expenses is the sum of total expenses for the following expense functions_x000D_
 Instruction (F3E011)_x000D_
 Research (F3E02A1)_x000D_
 Public service (F3E02B1)_x000D_
 Academic support (F3E03A1)_x000D_
 Student services (F3E03B1)_x000D_
 Institutional support (F3E03C1)_x000D_
 Net grant aid to students (F3E051) _x000D_
 Other expenses (F3E061) _x000D_
Total salaries and wage expenses is the sum of total expenses for the following expense functions_x000D_
 Instruction (F3E012)_x000D_
 Research (F3E02A2)_x000D_
 Public service (F3E02B2)_x000D_
 Academic support (F3E03A2)_x000D_
 Student services (F3E03B2)_x000D_
 Institutional support (F3E03C2)_x000D_
Other expenses (F3E062) _x000D_
 _x000D_
Total salary and wage expense is then divided by total core expenses._x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits,operations of plant, depreciation, interest and other expenses. _x000D_
For glossary definitions of the above finance terms see variables listed under the Finance survey.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries, wages, and benefit expenses as a percent of total expenses for private not-for-profit institutions  is derived as follows:_x000D_
Total Salaries and wage expenses (F3E072) plus employee fringe benefit expenses for institutional support (F3E073) divided by total expenses  (F3E071)._x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
Employee Fringe Benefits include all employee fringe benefits such as retirement plans, social security taxes, medical/dental plans, guaranteed disability income protection plans, tuition plans, housing plans, unemployment compensation plans, group life insurance plans, worker’s compensation plans, other in-kind benefits with cash options, and all other costs of employee benefits._x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits,operations of plant, depreciation, interest and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Salaries and wage expenses as a percent of total expenses for private not-for-profit institutions is derived as follows:_x000D_
Total Salaries and wage expenses (F3E072) divided by total expenses (F3E071)._x000D_
Salaries and wages are the amounts paid as compensation for services to all employees--faculty, staff, part time, full time, regular employees, and student employees. This includes regular or periodic payment to a person for the regular or periodic performance of work or a service and payment to a person for more sporadic performance of work or a service (overtime, extra compensation, summer compensation, bonuses, sick or annual leave, etc.)._x000D_
Employee Fringe Benefits include all employee fringe benefits such as retirement plans, social security taxes, medical/dental plans, guaranteed disability income protection plans, tuition plans, housing plans, unemployment compensation plans, group life insurance plans, worker’s compensation plans, other in-kind benefits with cash options, and all other costs of employee benefits._x000D_
Total expenses include expenses from salaries, wages, employee fringe benefits,operations of plant, depreciation, interest and other expenses.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Equity ratio for private-for profit institutions using Private for-profit standards is derived as follows:_x000D_
Total liabilities (F3A02) is subtracted from total assets (F3A01). This amount is then divided by total assets (F3A01)_x000D_
Liabilities are debts and obligations of the institution owed to outsiders or claims or rights, expressed in monetary terms, of an institution’s creditors. Two types of liabilities are often defined, short-term and long term. Short-term liabilities are those that will be satisfied or paid within one year. Long-term liabilities are those which will not be satisfied within a year. Liabilities include: 1) accounts payable; 2) deferred revenues and refundable advances; 3) Post-retirement and post-employment obligations; 4) other accrued liabilities; 5) annuity and life income obligations and other amounts held for the benefits of others; 6) bonds, notes, and capital leases payable and other long-term debt, including current portions; 7) government grants refundable under student loan programs; and 8) other liabilities (those liabilities not falling in one or more of the above seven categories). The exact categories of liabilities that must be used are not specified and the above are examples only. _x000D_
Assets  Physical items (tangible) or rights (intangible) that have value and that are owned by the institution. Assets are useful to the institution because they are a source of future services or because they can be used to secure future benefits.  Assets are usually divided into two categories, current and fixed. Current assets are those that can be readily turned into cash. Fixed assets are those which cannot readily be turned into cash without disrupting the operation of the institution. Fixed assets include intangible assets consisting of certain nonmaterial rights and benefits of an institution, such as patents, copyrights, trademarks and goodwill. Categories of assets include the following items: 1) cash, cash equivalents, and temporary investments; 2) receivables (net of allowance for uncollectible accounts); 3) inventories, prepaid expenses, and deferred charges; 4) amounts held by trustees for construction and debt services; 5) long-term investments; 6) plant, property, and equipment; and 7) other assets (those assets not falling in one ore more of the above six categories). The exact categories of assets that must be used are not specified and the above are examples only.</t></si><si><t>VarNumber</t></si><si><t>VarName</t></si><si><t>SUM</t></si><si><t>MEAN</t></si><si><t>MIN</t></si><si><t>MAX</t></si></sst>