<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<sst xmlns="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/spreadsheetml/2006/main" count="1950" uniqueCount="496"><si><t>varnumber</t></si><si><t>varname</t></si><si><t>DataType</t></si><si><t>Fieldwidth</t></si><si><t>format</t></si><si><t>imputationvar</t></si><si><t>varTitle</t></si><si><t>UNITID</t></si><si><t>N</t></si><si><t>Cont</t></si><si><t>Unique identification number of the institution</t></si><si><t>STAT_IC</t></si><si><t>Disc</t></si><si><t>Response status -  Institutional characteristics component</t></si><si><t>LOCK_IC</t></si><si><t>Status of IC component when institution was migrated</t></si><si><t>IMP_IC</t></si><si><t>Type of imputation method Institutional Characteristics</t></si><si><t>STAT_C</t></si><si><t>Response status -  Completions component</t></si><si><t>LOCK_C</t></si><si><t>Status of completions component when institution was migrated</t></si><si><t>PRCH_C</t></si><si><t>Parent/child indicator for completions</t></si><si><t>IDX_C</t></si><si><t>UnitID of Parent institution</t></si><si><t>PCC_F</t></si><si><t>Parent/child allocation factor - Completions</t></si><si><t>IMP_C</t></si><si><t>Type of imputation method Completions</t></si><si><t>STAT_E12</t></si><si><t>Response status of institution - 12-month enrollment</t></si><si><t>LOCK_E12</t></si><si><t>Status of 12-month enrollment component whe data collection closed</t></si><si><t>PRCH_E12</t></si><si><t>Parent/child indicator for 12-month enrollment</t></si><si><t>IDX_E12</t></si><si><t>ID number of parent institution - 12-month enrollment</t></si><si><t>PCE12_F</t></si><si><t>Parent/child allocation factor - 12-month enrollment</t></si><si><t>IMP_E12</t></si><si><t>Type of imputation method - 12 month enrollment</t></si><si><t>longDescription</t></si><si><t>Response status of the institution Fall Collection IC component</t></si><si><t>Imputation status of the institution - Institutional characteristics</t></si><si><t>Identifies Parent/child institutions for the Completions component   Parent records includes data for their institution and other campuses/institutions (child institutions). The child institution record will not have  data because it is included with the parent. The variable IDX_C contains the UNITID of the parent institution.</t></si><si><t>UNITID number of parent institution reporting Completions data  IDX_C contains the UNITID number of the parent institution institution. This data field is used to link child institutions  with the parent institution.</t></si><si><t>This value is the allocation factors for the Completions component.  These factors are provided by the parent instituion so that data reported by the parent can be allocated to the child campuses/institutions.</t></si><si><t>Type of imputation method used for imputing data for nonresponding institutions. Imputations methods include using reported data from the prior year; using reported data from another institution (Nearest Neighbor); and using Group median data from a similar group of institutions.</t></si><si><t>Status of 12-month Enrollment component when data collection closed</t></si><si><t>Identifies Parent/child institutions for the 12-month Enrollment component   Parent records includes data for their institution and other campuses/institutions (child institutions). The child institution record will not have  data because it is included with the parent. The variable IDX_EF contains the UNITID of the parent institution.</t></si><si><t>UNITID number of parent institution reporting 12-month enrollment data.  IDX_E12 contains the UNITID number of the parent institution institution. This data field is used to link child institutions  with the parent institution.</t></si><si><t>This value is the allocation factor for the 12-month Enrollment component.  The variable IDX_E12 contains the unitid of the parent or child, depending on the record type, that defines the relationship of the parent to it's children for the 12-month Enrollment component.</t></si><si><t>codevalue</t></si><si><t>valuelabel</t></si><si><t>frequency</t></si><si><t>percent</t></si><si><t>-2</t></si><si><t>1</t></si><si><t>Respondent</t></si><si><t>2</t></si><si><t>Partial respondent, imputed</t></si><si><t>3</t></si><si><t>Partial respondent, not imputed</t></si><si><t>4</t></si><si><t>Nonrespondent, imputed</t></si><si><t>5</t></si><si><t>Nonrespondent, not imputed</t></si><si><t>-9</t></si><si><t>Not active</t></si><si><t>0</t></si><si><t>No data</t></si><si><t>8</t></si><si><t>Complete, final lock applied</t></si><si><t>Not applicable</t></si><si><t>Carry forward (CF)</t></si><si><t>Response</t></si><si><t>Non respondent, imputed</t></si><si><t>No data submitted</t></si><si><t>Edited, some errors/warnings remain</t></si><si><t>Parent record includes data from child campuses</t></si><si><t>Child record - all data reported with parent campus</t></si><si><t>Nonrespondent not imputed</t></si><si><t>Child record - data reported with parent campus</t></si><si><t>Carry foreward (CF)</t></si><si><t>Nearest neighbor (NN)</t></si><si><t>n</t></si><si><t>sum</t></si><si><t>mean</t></si><si><t>min</t></si><si><t>max</t></si><si><t>Filename</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Provisional release 1:</t></si><si><t>Overview</t></si><si><t>Note</t></si><si><t>Contents of spreadsheet</t></si><si><t>Varlist</t></si><si><t>Variable list: Lists all variables in the table. Includes the variable name, variable label and the Data type, format and maximum field width of each variable.  The data type describes a variable as either a numeric (N) or Alphanumeric (A) and the format of a variable defines a variable as either continuous (Cont) or categorical (Disc).</t></si><si><t>Description</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Long description or glossary definition of a variable. </t></si><si><t>Frequencies</t></si><si><t>This worksheet contains the code values for of all categorical variables in the data file. It also lists the frequency and percent distribution for each code value by variable.</t></si><si><t>Statistics</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">This worksheet lists the sum, mean, minimum and maximum values of all continuous variables in the data file. </t></si><si><t>FLAGS2021</t></si><si><t>August 2022</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Provisional release data have undergone all NCES data quality control procedures. Data are imputed for nonresponding institutions. These data are used for First Look (Provisional Data) Web tables. Final release data include revisions to the provisional release data that have been made by institutions during the subsequent data collection year. The final release data can be used when the most up to date data are required; however, these data may not match First Look Web tables based on provisional data. </t></si><si><t>STAT_SFA</t></si><si><t>Response status for Student Financial Aid survey</t></si><si><t>LOCK_SFA</t></si><si><t>Status of Student Financial Aid Survey when data collection closed</t></si><si><t>PRCH_SFA</t></si><si><t>Parent/child indicator Student Financial Aid survey</t></si><si><t>IDX_SFA</t></si><si><t>ID number of parent institution Student Financial Aid</t></si><si><t>PCSFA_F</t></si><si><t>Parent/child allocation factor - Student Financial Aid</t></si><si><t>IMP_SFA</t></si><si><t>Type of imputation method Student Financial Aid</t></si><si><t>SFAFORM</t></si><si><t>SFA collection form type</t></si><si><t>STAT_GR</t></si><si><t>Response status - Graduation Rates</t></si><si><t>LOCK_GR</t></si><si><t>Status of Graduation rate survey when data collection closed</t></si><si><t>PRCH_GR</t></si><si><t>Parent/child indicator - Graduation Rates</t></si><si><t>IDX_GR</t></si><si><t>UNITID of parent institution reporting Graduation Rates</t></si><si><t>PCGR_F</t></si><si><t>Parent/child allocation factor - Graduation Rates</t></si><si><t>IMP_GR</t></si><si><t>Imputation method - Graduation Rates</t></si><si><t>COHRTSTU</t></si><si><t>Enrolled any full-time first-time students</t></si><si><t>STAT_GR2</t></si><si><t>Response status - Graduation Rates 200</t></si><si><t>LOCK_GR2</t></si><si><t>Status of Graduation rate 200 survey when data collection closed</t></si><si><t>PRCH_GR2</t></si><si><t>Parent/child indicator - Graduation Rates 200</t></si><si><t>IDX_GR2</t></si><si><t>UNITID of parent institution reporting Graduation Rates 200</t></si><si><t>PCGR2_F</t></si><si><t>Parent/child allocation factor - Graduation Rates 200</t></si><si><t>IMP_GR2</t></si><si><t>Imputation method - Graduation Rates 200</t></si><si><t>STAT_OM</t></si><si><t>Response status - Outcome Measures</t></si><si><t>LOCK_OM</t></si><si><t>Status of Outcome Measures component when data collection closed</t></si><si><t>PRCH_OM</t></si><si><t>Parent/child indicator - Outcome Measures</t></si><si><t>IDX_OM</t></si><si><t>UNITID of parent institution reporting Outcome Measures</t></si><si><t>PCOM_F</t></si><si><t>Parent/child allocation factor - Outcome Measures</t></si><si><t>IMP_OM</t></si><si><t>Imputations method - Outcome Measures</t></si><si><t>STAT_ADM</t></si><si><t>Response status - Admissions component</t></si><si><t>LOCK_ADM</t></si><si><t>Status of admissions component when institution was migrated</t></si><si><t>PRCH_ADM</t></si><si><t>Parent/child indicator for Admissions</t></si><si><t>IDX_ADM</t></si><si><t>ID number of parent institution - Admissions</t></si><si><t>PCADM_F</t></si><si><t>Parent/child allocation factor - Admissions</t></si><si><t>IMP_ADM</t></si><si><t>Type of imputation method - Admissions component</t></si><si><t>NTRLDSTR</t></si><si><t>Natural Disaster identification</t></si><si><t>Identifies Parent/child institutions for the Student Financial Aid component   Parent records includes data for their institution and other campuses/institutions (child institutions). The child institution record will not have  data because it is included with the parent. The variable IDX_SFA contains the UNITID of the parent institution.</t></si><si><t>UNITID number of parent institution reporting Student Financial Aid data  IDX_SFA contains the UNITID number of the parent institution institution. This data field is used to link child institutions  with the parent institution.</t></si><si><t>This value is the allocation factor for the Student Financial Aid component.  The variable IDX_SFA contains the unitid of the parent or child, depending on the record type, that defines the relationship of the parent to it's children for the Student Financial Aid component.</t></si><si><t>SFA collection form type - identifies survey screens</t></si><si><t>Response status of the institution to the Graduation Rates component of the winter data collection</t></si><si><t>Status of survey when data collection was closed</t></si><si><t>Identifies Parent/child institutions for the  Graduation Rates  component   Parent records includes data for their institution and other campuses/institutions (child institutions). The child institution record will not have  data because it is included with the parent. The variable IDX_GR contains the UNITID of the parent institution.</t></si><si><t>UNITID number of parent institution reporting Graduation Rate data.  IDX_GR contains the UNITID number of the parent institution institution. This data field is used to link child institutions  with the parent institution.</t></si><si><t>This value is the allocation factor for the Graduation Rates component.  The variable IDX_GR contains the unitid of the parent or child, depending on the record type, that defines the relationship of the parent to it's children for the Graduation Rates component.</t></si><si><t>For the Cohort year, Did your institution enroll any full-time first-time students? Cohort year=Academic year  2011-12 for 4-year institutions and 2014-15 for both 2-year and less-than-2-year institutions.</t></si><si><t>Identifies Parent/child institutions for the  Graduation Rates 200  component   Parent records includes data for their institution and other campuses/institutions (child institutions). The child institution record will not have  data because it is included with the parent. The variable IDX_GR2 contains the UNITID of the parent institution.</t></si><si><t>UNITID number of parent institution reporting Graduation Rate 200 data.  IDX_GR2 contains the UNITID number of the parent institution institution. This data field is used to link child institutions  with the parent institution.</t></si><si><t>This value is the allocation factor for the Graduation Rates 200 component.  The variable IDX_GR2 contains the unitid of the parent or child, depending on the record type, that defines the relationship of the parent to it's children for the Graduation Rates 200 component.</t></si><si><t>Response status of the institution to the Outcome measures component of the winter data collection</t></si><si><t>Status of survey component when data collection was closed</t></si><si><t>Identifies Parent/child institutions for the Outcome Measures component   Parent records includes data for their institution and other campuses/institutions (child institutions). The child institution record will not have  data because it is included with the parent. The variable IDX_OM contains the UNITID of the parent institution.</t></si><si><t>UNITID number of parent institution reporting Graduation Rate data.  IDX_OM contains the UNITID number of the parent institution institution reporting Outcome Measures. This data field is used to link child institutions  with the parent institution.</t></si><si><t>This value is the allocation factor for the Outcome Measures component.  The variable IDX_OM contains the unitid of the parent or child, depending on the record type, that defines the relationship of the parent to it's children for the Outcome Measures component.</t></si><si><t>Response status of the institution Winter collection Admissions component</t></si><si><t>Identifies Parent/child institutions for the Admissions component   Parent records includes data for their institution and other campuses/institutions (child institutions). The child institution record will not have  data because it is included with the parent. The variable IDX_ADM contains the UNITID of the parent institution.</t></si><si><t>This value is the allocation factors for the Admissions component.  These factors are provided by the parent instituion so that data reported by the parent can be allocated to the child campuses/institutions.</t></si><si><t>Identifies institutions that may have been affected by natural disaster's such as hurricanes, tsunamis, fires, etc. This variable can be used to explain possible anomalies in the reporting of IPEDS data.</t></si><si><t>Parent record - includes data from branch campuses</t></si><si><t>Undergraduate student financial and undergraduate military servicemembers/veteran's benefits are applicable</t></si><si><t>Undergraduate student financial and undergraduate and graduate military servicemembers/veteran's benefits are applicable</t></si><si><t>Graduate military servicemembers/veteran's benefits screens are applicable</t></si><si><t>Complete</t></si><si><t>Parent record -  includes data from child campuses</t></si><si><t>Child record - data reported at parent campus</t></si><si><t>Yes</t></si><si><t>No, did not enroll full-time, first-time (undergraduate) students</t></si><si><t>No, did not offer programs at or below the baccalaureate level</t></si><si><t>No, institution was not in operation in cohort year</t></si><si><t>-1</t></si><si><t>Not reported</t></si><si><t>LOCk_OM</t></si><si><t>Edited</t></si><si><t>No</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Provisional release 2:</t></si><si><t>October 2022</t></si><si><t>STAT_HR</t></si><si><t>Response status of institution for Human Resources (HR) component</t></si><si><t>LOCK_HR</t></si><si><t>Status of Human Resources (HR) component when data collection closed</t></si><si><t>PRCH_HR</t></si><si><t>Parent/child  indicator - Human Resources (HR) component</t></si><si><t>IDX_HR</t></si><si><t>ID of institution where data are reported for the Human Resources (HR) component</t></si><si><t>PCHR_F</t></si><si><t>Parent/child allocation factor - HR</t></si><si><t>IMP_HR</t></si><si><t>Type of Imputation method - Human Resources (HR) component</t></si><si><t>FTEMP15</t></si><si><t>Does institution have 15 or more full-time employees</t></si><si><t>TENURSYS</t></si><si><t>Does institution have a tenure system</t></si><si><t>SA_EXCL</t></si><si><t>Salary exclusion</t></si><si><t>STAT_EAP</t></si><si><t>Response status for EAP</t></si><si><t>STAT_SA</t></si><si><t>Response status to SA survey</t></si><si><t>STAT_S</t></si><si><t>Response status for Fall Staff</t></si><si><t>STAT_EF</t></si><si><t>Response status of institution -  Fall enrollment</t></si><si><t>LOCK_EF</t></si><si><t>Status of Fall Enrollment survey when data collection closed</t></si><si><t>PRCH_EF</t></si><si><t>Parent/child indicator f- Fall enrollment</t></si><si><t>IDX_EF</t></si><si><t>ID number of parent institution - Fall enrollment</t></si><si><t>PCEF_F</t></si><si><t>Parent/child allocation factor - Fall enrollment</t></si><si><t>IMP_EF</t></si><si><t>Type of imputation method - Fall enrollment</t></si><si><t>PTA99_EF</t></si><si><t>Status enrollment by race/ethnicity (99.0000 CIP)</t></si><si><t>PTACIPEF</t></si><si><t>Status enrollment by major</t></si><si><t>PTB_EF</t></si><si><t>Status enrollment summary by age</t></si><si><t>PTC_EF</t></si><si><t>Status residence of first-time first-year students</t></si><si><t>PTD_EF</t></si><si><t>Status total entering class and retention rates</t></si><si><t>STAT_F</t></si><si><t>Response status for Finance survey</t></si><si><t>LOCK_F</t></si><si><t>Status of Finance survey when data collection closed</t></si><si><t>PRCH_F</t></si><si><t>Parent/child indicator - Finance</t></si><si><t>IDX_F</t></si><si><t>ID number of parent institution - Finance</t></si><si><t>PCF_F</t></si><si><t>Parent/child allocation factor - Finance</t></si><si><t>PRCHTP_F</t></si><si><t>Parent/child system indicator - Finance</t></si><si><t>IMP_F</t></si><si><t>Type of imputation method  Finance</t></si><si><t>FORM_F</t></si><si><t>Identifies reporting standards GASB, FASB, or modified FASB(for-profit institutions) used to report finance data</t></si><si><t>FYBEG</t></si><si><t>A</t></si><si><t>Beginning date of fiscal year covered (all finance)</t></si><si><t>FYEND</t></si><si><t>End date of fiscal year covered  (all finance)</t></si><si><t>GPFS</t></si><si><t>Audit Opinion GPFS from auditor (all finance)</t></si><si><t>F1GASBAL</t></si><si><t>GASB alternative accounting model</t></si><si><t>F2PELL</t></si><si><t>Account for Pell grants as pass through transactions or as federal grant revenues to the institution (FASB  institutions)?</t></si><si><t>F3PELL</t></si><si><t>Account for Pell grants as pass through transactions or as federal grant revenues to the institution (private-for-profit institutions)?</t></si><si><t>F_ATHLTC</t></si><si><t>Are intercollegiate athletic expenses accounted for as auxiliary enterprises or treated as student services</t></si><si><t>F_ATHRV1</t></si><si><t>Are intercollegiate athletic revenues included with sales and services of educational activities</t></si><si><t>F_ATHRV2</t></si><si><t>Are intercollegiate athletic revenues included with sales and services of auxiliary enterprises</t></si><si><t>F_ATHRV3</t></si><si><t>Does not have intercollegiate athletics revenues</t></si><si><t>F_ATHRV9</t></si><si><t>Are intercollegiate athletic revenues included with a source other than educational activities or auxiliary enterprises</t></si><si><t>F3BIST</t></si><si><t>Type of business structure for tax purposes (private-for-profit, degree-granting institutions)</t></si><si><t>STAT_AL</t></si><si><t>Response status -  Academic Libraries component</t></si><si><t>LOCK_AL</t></si><si><t>Status of Academic Library component when institution was migrated</t></si><si><t>PRCH_AL</t></si><si><t>Parent/child indicator for Academic Libraries</t></si><si><t>IDX_AL</t></si><si><t>UnitID of Parent institution - Academic Libraries</t></si><si><t>PCAL_F</t></si><si><t>Parent/child allocation factor - Academic Libraries</t></si><si><t>IMP_AL</t></si><si><t>Type of imputation method - Academic Libraries</t></si><si><t>HASAL</t></si><si><t>Has an academic library</t></si><si><t>Response status of institution for Human Resource ( HR)  component.  HR  include Employee by Assigned Position, Salaries, and  Fall Staff.</t></si><si><t>Status of the Human Resource (HR) component  when data collection closed. HR  include Employee by Assigned Position, Salaries, and  Fall Staff.</t></si><si><t>Identifies Parent/child institutions for the  Human Resources component   Parent records includes data for their institution and other campuses/institutions (child institutions). The child institution record will not have  data because it is included with the parent. The variable IDX_HR contains the UNITID of the parent institution. HR  include Employee by Assigned Position, Salaries, and  Fall Staff.</t></si><si><t>UNITID number of parent institution reporting Human Resource (HR) data.  IDX_HR contains the UNITID number of the parent institution institution. This data field is used to link child institutions  with the parent institution.  HR  include Employee by Assigned Position, Salaries, and  Fall Staff.</t></si><si><t>This value is the allocation factor for the Employees by Assigned Position component.  The variable IDX_EAP contains the unitid of the parent or child, depending on the record type, that defines the relationship of the parent to it's children for the Employees by Assigned Position component.  The variable PCEAP_M contains the method used to create this allocation factor.</t></si><si><t>Response status for Employee by Assigned Position  Survey</t></si><si><t>Response status to the Faculty Salary survey</t></si><si><t>Response status for Fall Staff Survey</t></si><si><t>Identifies Parent/child institutions for the  Fall Enrollment component   Parent records includes data for their institution and other campuses/institutions (child institutions). The child institution record will not have  data because it is included with the parent. The variable IDX_EF contains the UNITID of the parent institution.</t></si><si><t>This value is the allocation factor for the Fall Enrollment component.  The variable IDX_EF contains the unitid of the parent or child, depending on the record type, that defines the relationship of the parent to it's children for the Fall Enrollment component.</t></si><si><t>Part A, 99.0000 CIP, enrollment by racial/ethnic categories
1 - Part response
3 - Part nonresponse, not imputed
4 - Part nonresponse, imputed
-2 - Item not applicable
-7 - Part nonresponse, closed
-9 -  not active</t></si><si><t>Part B, enrollment summary by age (collected odd years only)
1 - Part response
3 - Part nonresponse, not imputed
4 - Part nonresponse, imputed
-2 - Item not applicable
-6 - Part not applicable
-7 - Part nonresponse, closed
-9 -  not active</t></si><si><t>Part C, total-first time, first-year students, by residence (collected even years only)
1 - Part response
3 - Part nonresponse, not imputed
-2 - Item not applicable
-6 - Part not applicable
-7 - Part nonresponse, closed
-9 - not active</t></si><si><t>Status total entering class</t></si><si><t>Identifies Parent/child institutions for the Finance component   Parent records includes data for their institution and other campuses/institutions (child institutions). The child institution record will not have  data because it is included with the parent. The variable IDX_F contains the UNITID of the parent institution.</t></si><si><t>UNITID number of parent institution reporting Finance data  IDX_F contains the UNITID number of the parent institution institution. This data field is used to link child institutions  with the parent institution.</t></si><si><t>This value is the allocation factor for the Finance component.  The variable IDX_F contains the unitid of the parent or child, depending on the record type, that defines the relationship of the parent to it's children for the Finance component.  The variable PCF_M contains the method used to create this allocation factor.</t></si><si><t>Identifies the type of parent/child relationship for the system

1=Full parent child system - All children campuses (PRCH_F=2) finance data are reported by the Parent institution (PRCH_F=1) as identified by the IDX_F variable (Unitid reporting finance data)

2=Partial child system (1) – Has children campuses (PRCH_F=3) that report their own current funds, revenues and expenses, but assets, liabilities and other system wide information are reported by the parent institution (PRCH_F=1) as identified by the IDX_F variable. Can include children institutions (PRCH_F=2) that report all finance data with the parent institution.

3=Partial child system (2) -  Has children campuses (PRCH_F=3) that report their own current funds, revenues and expenses, but assets, liabilities and other system wide information are reported by the parent institution (PRCH_F=1)  as identified by the IDX_F variable.  This Partial system will include one or more child campus (PRCH_F=2)  whose current funds revenues and expenses are reported by one of the partial campuses. In this case the IDX_F variable for this child campus will have the UNITID of the reporting partial campus. Partial reporting children campuses that also act as a parent institution for other child campuses are identied as (PRCH_F=6).

5 – Partial child system of a non IPEDS institution.  These campuses only report revenues and expenses, but assets, liabilities and other system wide information are reported by an entity that is out of the scope of IPEDS, such as a hospital or state local training centers.</t></si><si><t>Indicate which reporting (accounting) standards are used to prepare your financial statements</t></si><si><t>Fiscal calendar year: Beginning month and year for the 12-month fiscal year that this report covers</t></si><si><t>Fiscal calendar year: Ending month and year for the 12-month fiscal year that this report covers</t></si><si><t>Did your institution receive an unqualified opinion on its General Purpose Financial Statements from your auditor for the fiscal year noted above? (If your institution is audited only in combination with another entity, answer this question based on the audit of that entity.)</t></si><si><t>GASB Statement No. 34 offers three alternative reporting models for special-purpose governments like colleges and universities. Which model will be implemented by your institution? (Applicable to institutions using GASB)</t></si><si><t>Does your institution account for Pell grants as pass through transactions (a simple payment on the student's account) or as federal grant revenues to the institution?

Pell Grants: under FASB standards institutions have the option to report Pell grants as federal revenue and scholarships (or allowances) or as a pass-through transaction, essentially a payment on the student's account. The latter option is sometimes referred to as an agency transaction. Please indicate whether the institution accounts for Pell grants as pass-through payments or as federal revenue. If the institution does not award Pell grants, select the applicable option.</t></si><si><t>Does your institution account for Pell grants as pass through transactions (a simple payment on the student's account) or as federal grant revenues to the institution?</t></si><si><t>If your institution participates in intercollegiate athletics, indicate the category where these revenues are included (check all that apply):
	  - Sales and services of educational activities
  - Sales and services of auxiliary enterprises
  - Other sources
  - Does not have intercollegiate athletics revenue

Please indicate where your institution allocates revenues for intercollegiate athletics, with sales and services of educational activities, sales and services of auxiliary enterprises, other revenue category, or if the institution does not participate in intercollegiate athletics</t></si><si><t>What type of business structure is the institution for tax purposes? 

Private for-profit degree-granting institutions with a business structure of either C Corporation or a Limited Liability Company (LLC) are required to report Federal, and State and Local income tax expenditures.</t></si><si><t>Identifies Parent/child institutions for the Academic Libraries component   Parent records includes data for their institution and other campuses/institutions (child institutions). The child institution record will not have  data because it is included with the parent. The variable IDX_AL contains the UNITID of the parent institution.</t></si><si><t>UNITID number of parent institution reporting Academic Libraries data  IDX_AL contains the UNITID number of the parent institution institution. This data field is used to link child institutions  with the parent institution.</t></si><si><t>This value is the allocation factors for the Academic Libraries component.  These factors are provided by the parent instituion so that data reported by the parent can be allocated to the child campuses/institutions.</t></si><si><t>Identifies if institution has an academic library. Degree-granting institutions were asked to report total library expenditures on the Institutional characteristic header component during the registration process. If expenditures are greater than zero, institutions are determined to have an academic library, and therefore required to report academic library data.</t></si><si><t>Has tenure system</t></si><si><t>No tenure system</t></si><si><t>Partial respondent imputed</t></si><si><t>Nonrespondent imputed</t></si><si><t>Has data, not edited</t></si><si><t>{Not active}</t></si><si><t>Partial child record - reports revenues/expenses. Assets/liabilties reported with parent</t></si><si><t>6</t></si><si><t>Child record - reports partial data but other data is included  with entity that is not a postsecondary institution</t></si><si><t>Full parent/child system</t></si><si><t>Partial parent child system (1)</t></si><si><t>Partial parent child system (2)</t></si><si><t>System with partial reporting children campuses of NON-IPEDS entity</t></si><si><t>GASB Reporting Standards 34/35</t></si><si><t>FASB Reporting Standards</t></si><si><t>Private for-profit institutions</t></si><si><t>112019</t></si><si><t>November 2019</t></si><si><t>122019</t></si><si><t>December 2019</t></si><si><t>012020</t></si><si><t>January 2020</t></si><si><t>022020</t></si><si><t>February 2020</t></si><si><t>032020</t></si><si><t>March 2020</t></si><si><t>042020</t></si><si><t>April 2020</t></si><si><t>052020</t></si><si><t>May 2020</t></si><si><t>062020</t></si><si><t>June 2020</t></si><si><t>072020</t></si><si><t>July 2020</t></si><si><t>082020</t></si><si><t>August 2020</t></si><si><t>092020</t></si><si><t>September 2020</t></si><si><t>102020</t></si><si><t>October 2020</t></si><si><t>112020</t></si><si><t>November 2020</t></si><si><t>122020</t></si><si><t>December 2020</t></si><si><t>012021</t></si><si><t>January 2021</t></si><si><t>022021</t></si><si><t>February 2021</t></si><si><t>032021</t></si><si><t>March 2021</t></si><si><t>042021</t></si><si><t>April 2021</t></si><si><t>052021</t></si><si><t>May 2021</t></si><si><t>062021</t></si><si><t>June 2021</t></si><si><t>072021</t></si><si><t>July 2021</t></si><si><t>082021</t></si><si><t>August 2021</t></si><si><t>092021</t></si><si><t>September 2021</t></si><si><t>Yes (unqualified)</t></si><si><t>No (qualified)</t></si><si><t>Do not know</t></si><si><t>Business Type Activities</t></si><si><t>Governmental Activities</t></si><si><t>Governmental Activities with Business-Type Activities</t></si><si><t>Pass through (agency)</t></si><si><t>Federal grants</t></si><si><t>Does not award Pell grants</t></si><si><t>Auxiliary enterprises</t></si><si><t>Student services</t></si><si><t>Does not participate in intercollegiate athletics</t></si><si><t>Other</t></si><si><t>Yes, included with sales and services of educational activities</t></si><si><t>Not included with sales and services of educational activities</t></si><si><t>Yes, included with sales and services of auxiliary enterprises</t></si><si><t>Not included with sales and services of auxiliary enterprises</t></si><si><t>Does not have athletic revenues</t></si><si><t>Has athletic revenues</t></si><si><t>Yes, included with sources other than sales and services</t></si><si><t>Not included with sources other than sales and services</t></si><si><t>Sole Proprietorship</t></si><si><t>Partnership (General, Limited, Limited Liability)</t></si><si><t>C Corporation</t></si><si><t>S Corporation</t></si><si><t>Limited Liability Company (LLC)</t></si><si><t>No access to library collections and no library expenses</t></si><si><t>Has data not edited</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Provisional release 3:</t></si><si><t>December 2022</t></si><si><t>REV_IC</t></si><si><t>REV_C</t></si><si><t>REV_E12</t></si><si><t>Revision status - Completions</t></si><si><t>Revision status - 12-month enrollment</t></si><si><t>Identifies institutions that submitted revised 2021-22 institutional characteristics data using the 2021-22 Prior Year Data Revision system.   

Institutions were only allowed to submit revisions for questions included in Part B - Services and Programs for Servicemembers and Veterans and Part C - Student Services - Special Learning Opportunities, which include types of credits accepted, special learning opportunities, student services, distance education, alternative tuition plans and undergraduate students enrolled who are formerly registered with office of disability services.</t></si><si><t>Identifies institutions that submitted revised completions data for July 1, 2020 through June 30, 2021 using the IPEDS 2021-22 Prior Year Data Revision system</t></si><si><t>Identifies institutions that submitted revised 12-month enrollment data for 2020-21 using the IPEDS 2021-22 Prior Year Data Revision system</t></si><si><t>Submitted revised data</t></si><si><t>Did not submit revised data</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Revised release 1:</t></si><si><t>August 2023</t></si><si><t>REV_SFA</t></si><si><t>Revision status - Student Financial Aid</t></si><si><t>REV_GR</t></si><si><t>Revision status - Graduation Rates</t></si><si><t>REV_GR2</t></si><si><t>Revision status - Graduation Rates 200</t></si><si><t>REV_OM</t></si><si><t>Revision status - Outcome Measures</t></si><si><t>REV_ADM</t></si><si><t>Identifies institutions that submitted revised 2020-21 student financial aid data using the 2021-22 Prior Year Data Revision system</t></si><si><t>Identifies institutions that submitted revised graduation rate data, status date August 31, 2021 using the 2021-22 Prior Year Data Revision system</t></si><si><t>Identifies institutions that submitted revised graduation rate 200 data, status date August 31, 2021 using the 2021-22 Prior Year Data Revision system</t></si><si><t>Identifies institutions that submitted revised outcome measures data, status date August 31, 2021 using the 2021-22 Prior Year Data Revision system</t></si><si><t>Identifies institutions that submitted revised 2021-22 admissions data using the 2021-22 Prior Year Data Revision system</t></si><si><t>Not applicable, revised OM data not released</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Revised release 2:</t></si><si><t>November 2023</t></si><si><t>(Revised release 3 )</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Revised release 3:</t></si><si><t>December 2023</t></si><si><r><t xml:space="preserve">This file contains response status information for every institution in the 2021-22 IPEDS universe. This file will determine institutions that have responded; institutions that did not respond and have imputed data; and survey applicability.  It will also identify institutions whose data represents multiple campuses (parent/child reporting).  

</t></r><r><rPr><b/><sz val="10"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t>Provisional release 1</t></r><r><rPr><sz val="10"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve"> includes information from the provisional release for the fall survey components:   Institutional Characteristics 2021-22, Completions and 12-month enrollment 2020-21.
</t></r><r><rPr><b/><sz val="10"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t>Provisional release 2</t></r><r><rPr><sz val="10"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve"> updates release 1 with the provisional release of the winter survey components: Admissions Fall 2021, Graduation Rates 150, Graduation Rates 200 and Outcome Measures, Status date: August 31, 2021 and Student Financial Aid 2020-21.
</t></r><r><rPr><b/><sz val="10"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t>Provisional release 3</t></r><r><rPr><sz val="10"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve"> updates release 2  with the provisional release of  the spring survey components: Fall enrollment 2021-22, Human Resources 2021-22, Finance and Academic Libraries Fiscal year 2021. 
</t></r><r><rPr><b/><sz val="10"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t>Revised release 1</t></r><r><rPr><sz val="10"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve"> identifies institutions that submitted revisions for Institutional Characteristics (Special learning opportunities, selected services, information on Veterans and service members and Undergraduate Disabilities)  2021-22 and/or the Completions and 12-month enrollment 2020-21 components.
</t></r><r><rPr><b/><sz val="10"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t>Revised release 2</t></r><r><rPr><sz val="10"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve"> identifies institutions that submitted revisions for Admissions Fall 2021, Graduation Rates 150, Graduation Rates 200 and Outcome Measures, Status date: August 31, 2021 and Student Financial Aid 2020-21.
</t></r><r><rPr><b/><sz val="10"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t>Revised release 3</t></r><r><rPr><sz val="10"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve"> identifies institutions that submitted revisions for Fall enrollment 2021-22, Human Resources 2021-22, Finance and Academic Libraries Fiscal year 2021. 

</t></r></si><si><t>File Documentation for the IPEDS response status data for all survey components, 2021-22</t></si><si><t/></si><si><t>Revision status - Institutional Characteristics</t></si><si><t>Revision status - Admissions</t></si><si><t>REV_HR</t></si><si><t>REV_EF</t></si><si><t>REV_F</t></si><si><t>REV_AL</t></si><si><t>Response status of the institution</t></si><si><t>UNITID number of parent institution reporting Admissions data  IDX_ADM contains the UNITID number of the parent institution institution. This data field is used to link child institutions  with the parent institution.</t></si><si><t>Does institution have 15 or more full-time employees? FULL-TIME STAFF (EMPLOYEES) - The type of appointment at the snapshot date determines whether an employee is full time or part time. The employee's term of contract is not considered in making the determination of full or part time. Employees are counted only once even if employed multiple ways (e.g., a full-time employee who also teaches part time on a per course basis is counted only as full time). Also, a full-time employee who has an additional overload part-time appointment, contract, or course payment is counted as full time. (If Institution has less than 15 full-time employes the Fall staff survey is not applicable).</t></si><si><t>Does institution have a tenure system?

Does institution have a tenure system?

This variable is derived so that users can disaggregate those employees that are nontenured not on tenure track from those employees that are in an institution with no tenure system. Both EAP and Fall Staff components collect these data using 1 data  field which makes it very difficult to produce tables on tenure.  It is assumed that if all employees are reported in the nontenured not on track/no tenure system column/row, then the institution has no tenure system. If the institution reports at least 1 employee as tenured or nontenured, on tenure track then the institution has a tenure system. This variable can be used in the IPEDS DAS to produce tables on tenure status.  See derivation below: 

All employees, Tenured faculty (EAPTOT,EAPRECTP= 1102 ) &gt; 0  
or  All employees, Non-tenured faculty, on tenure track (EAPTOT,EAPRECTP=1103) &gt; 0 
then TENURSYS=1 (Has tenure system).
ELSE TENURSYS=0 (No tenure system)</t></si><si><t>Do all of the instructional faculty at your institution fall into any of the following categories?
All are part time 
All are military personnel 
All contribute their services (e.g., member of a religious order) 
All teach pre-clinical or clinical medicine. If all instructional faculty fall into any of these categories the Faculty Salary survey is not applicable.</t></si><si><t>UNITID number of parent institution reporting Fall enrollment  data  IDX_EF contains the UNITID number of the parent institution institution. This data field is used to link child institutions  with the parent institution.</t></si><si><t>If your institution participates in intercollegiate athletics, are the expenses accounted for as auxiliary enterprises or treated as student services?  

Intercollegiate Athletics: according to NACUBO descriptions of functional expenses, intercollegiate athletics may be treated as auxiliary enterprises (if operated as an essentially self-supporting operation) or as student services (if the program is not operated as an essentially self-supporting operation). Please indicate whether your institution treats expenses for intercollegiate athletics as auxiliary enterprises, as student services, or in another functional category, or if the institution does not participate in intercollegiate athletics. This question is optional for the fiscal year 2005 collection.</t></si><si><t>Partial parent/child record - reports revenues/expenses that also includes data from other branch campuses. Assets/liabilties reported with parent</t></si><si><t>Yes, have access to library collections and have library expenses</t></si><si><t>Yes, have access to library collections, but no library expenses</t></si><si><t>Revision status - Human Resources</t></si><si><t>Revision status - Fall Enrollment</t></si><si><t>Revision status - Finance</t></si><si><t>Revision status - Academic Libraries</t></si><si><t>Identifies institutions that submitted revised 2021-22 human resources data using the 2021-22 Prior Year Data Revision system</t></si><si><t>Identifies institutions that submitted revised fall 2021 enrollment data using the IPEDS 2021-22 Prior Year Data Revision system</t></si><si><t>Identifies institutions that submitted revised finance data, fiscal year 2021 using the 2021-22 Prior Year Data Revision system</t></si><si><t>Identifies institutions that submitted revised academic library data, fiscal year 2021 using the 2021-22 Prior Year Data Revision system</t></si></sst>