<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<sst xmlns="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/spreadsheetml/2006/main" count="222" uniqueCount="121"><si><t>Filename</t></si><si><t>Overview</t></si><si><t>Note</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Preliminary release data have been edited but are subject to further NCES quality control procedures. Imputed data for nonresponding institutions are not included. These data are used for First Look (Preliminary Data) publications. Provisional release data have undergone all NCES data quality control procedures. Data are imputed for nonresponding institutions. These data are used for First Look (Provisional Data) publications. Final release data include revisions to the provisional release data that have been made by institutions during the subsequent data collection year. The final release data can be used when the most up to date data are required; however, these data may not match tables from the First Look reports based on preliminary and provisional data. </t></si><si><t>Contents of spreadsheet</t></si><si><t>Varlist</t></si><si><t>Variable list: Lists all variables in the table. Includes the variable name, variable label and the Data type, format and maximum field width of each variable.  The data type describes a variable as either a numeric (N) or Alphanumeric (A) and the format of a variable defines a variable as either continuous (Cont) or categorical (Disc).  It all also lists the variable name of all imputation flag variables for each continuous variable. Imputation flag variable describes whether a value for the corresponding variable was reported, imputed or not applicable.</t></si><si><t>Description</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Long description or glossary definition of a variable. </t></si><si><t>Frequencies</t></si><si><t>Statistics</t></si><si><t>varnumber</t></si><si><t>varname</t></si><si><t>DataType</t></si><si><t>Fieldwidth</t></si><si><t>format</t></si><si><t>imputationvar</t></si><si><t>varTitle</t></si><si><t>UNITID</t></si><si><t>N</t></si><si><t>Cont</t></si><si><t>Unique identification number of the institution</t></si><si><t>CDACTUA</t></si><si><t>XCDACTUA</t></si><si><t>12-month instructional activity credit hours: undergraduates</t></si><si><t>CNACTUA</t></si><si><t>XCNACTUA</t></si><si><t>12-month instructional activity contact hours: undergraduates</t></si><si><t>CDACTGA</t></si><si><t>XCDACTGA</t></si><si><t>12-month instructional activity credit hours: graduates</t></si><si><t>EFTEUG</t></si><si><t>XEFTEUG</t></si><si><t>EFTEGD</t></si><si><t>XEFTEGD</t></si><si><t>FTEUG</t></si><si><t>XFTEUG</t></si><si><t>FTEGD</t></si><si><t>XFTEGD</t></si><si><t>FTEDPP</t></si><si><t>XFTEDPP</t></si><si><t>ACTTYPE</t></si><si><t>Disc</t></si><si><t>Is instructional activity based on credit or contact hours</t></si><si><t>longDescription</t></si><si><t>codevalue</t></si><si><t>valuelabel</t></si><si><t>frequency</t></si><si><t>percent</t></si><si><t>1</t></si><si><t>Contact hours</t></si><si><t>2</t></si><si><t>Credit hours</t></si><si><t>3</t></si><si><t>Both contact and credit hours</t></si><si><t>-2</t></si><si><t>Not applicable</t></si><si><t>n</t></si><si><t>sum</t></si><si><t>mean</t></si><si><t>min</t></si><si><t>max</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">File Documentation for the 12-month Instructional Activity Data File, 2014-15 </t></si><si><t>EFIA2015</t></si><si><t>Estimated full-time equivalent (FTE) undergraduate enrollment, 2014-15</t></si><si><t>Estimated full-time equivalent (FTE) graduate enrollment, 2014-15</t></si><si><t>Reported full-time equivalent (FTE) undergraduate enrollment, 2014-15</t></si><si><t>Reported full-time equivalent (FTE) graduate enrollment, 2014-15</t></si><si><t>Reported full-time equivalent (FTE) doctors professional practice, 2014-15</t></si><si><t>12-Month Enrollment and Instructional Activity                            
Credit Hour Activity for academic programs: Undergraduate Programs        
Related glossary links                                                    
CREDIT HOUR ACTIVITY - The provision of coursework to students which  can be measured in terms of credit hours. For the purposes of this        
survey, total credit hour activity was determined by multiplying the  credit hour value of the course by the number of students enrolled in     
the course for credit. For example, the credit hour activity for a  3-credit course with an enrollment of 30 students is 90 credit hours.     
Using this as a guide, institutions were asked to compute the credit  hours attempted for each course and sum the activity for all credit       
hour courses over the total 12-month period. Enrollment is based on  the number of students enrolled at the close of the official drop/add     
period or other census date of the institution.                           
INSTRUCTIONAL ACTIVITY - The provision of coursework to students which  can be measured in various terms.                                         
CREDIT - Recognition of attendance or performance in an instructional  activity (course or program) that can be applied by a recipient toward  the requirements for a degree, diploma, certificate, or other formal  award.</t></si><si><t>12-Month Enrollment and Instructional Activity                            
Contact Hour Activity for occupational (undergraduate) programs           
Related glossary links                                                    
CONTACT HOUR ACTIVITY - The provision of coursework to students which  can be measured in terms of contact or clock hours. For the purposes    of this survey, total contact hour activity was determined by  multiplying the contact hour value of the program by the number of  students enrolled in the program. For example, a 600 hour program with  6 students enrolled would contribute 3600 contact hours to the total  12-month activity as long as all 3600 hours were completed during the  timeframe. However,if 3 students completed their program but the remaining 3 only completed half the program, the institution should report 1,800 hours for the first three students and 900 hours for the  second group; or a total of 2,700 hours toward the 12-month total.        
INSTRUCTIONAL ACTIVITY - The provision of coursework to students which  can be measured in various terms.                                         
CREDIT - Recognition of attendance or performance in an instructional activity (course or program) that can be applied by a recipient toward  the requirements for a degree, diploma, certificate, or other formal  award.</t></si><si><t>12-Month Enrollment and Instructional Activity                            
Credit Hour Activity for academic programs: Graduate Programs             
Related glossary links                                                    
CREDIT HOUR ACTIVITY - The provision of coursework to students which  can be measured in terms of credit hours. For the purposes of this        
survey, total credit hour activity was determined by multiplying the credit hour value of the course by the number of students enrolled in  the course for credit. For example, the credit hour activity for a  3-credit course with an enrollment of 30 students is 90 credit hours.    Using this as a guide, institutions were asked to compute the credit  hours attempted for each course and sum the activity for all credit  hour courses over the total 12-month period. enrollment is based on the number of students enrolled at the close of the official drop/add     
period or other census date of the institution.                           
INSTRUCTIONAL ACTIVITY - The provision of coursework to students which  can be measured in various terms.                                         
CREDIT - Recognition of attendance or performance in an instructional activity (course or program) that can be applied by a recipient toward  the requirements for a degree, diploma, certificate, or other formal  award.</t></si><si><t>Estimated full-time equivalent (FTE) undergraduate enrollment, academic year 2014-15

Estimated full-time equivalent undergraduate enrollment was generated as follows:

For institutions with a semester, trimester, or 4-1-4 plan, the number of FTE undergraduate is the sum of undergraduate credit hours divided by 30 and contact hours divided by 900. For institutions with a quarter plan, undergraduate undergraduate credit hours divided by 45 and contact hours divided by 900. For institutions with continuous enrollment over a 12-month period, undergraduate credit hours were divided by 30 and contact hours were divided by 900.</t></si><si><t>Estimated full-time equivalent (FTE) graduate enrollment, academic year 2014-15

Estimated full-time equivalent graduate enrollment was generated as follows:

For institutions with a semester, trimester, or 4-1-4 plan, the number of FTE graduate students is the number of graduate credit hours divided by 24. For institutions with a quarter plan, graduate FTE is the is the number ofgraduate credit hours divided by 36.</t></si><si><t>Reported full-time equivalent (FTE) undergraduate enrollment, academic year 2014-15

NCES uses estimated FTE undergraduate enrollment to calculate expenses by function per FTE and core revenues per FTE as reported in the IPEDS Data Feedback Report.

If the generated estimate was not reasonable, the institution provided their best estimate for undergraduate FTE.  If the institution did not provide an FTE, then the reported FTE was set to the estimated FTE.</t></si><si><t>Reported full-time equivalent (FTE) graduate enrollment, academic year 2014-15

NCES uses estimated FTE graduate enrollment to calculate expenses by function per FTE and core revenues per FTE as reported in the IPEDS Data Feedback Report.

If the generated estimate was not reasonable, the institution provided their best estimate for graduate FTE.  If the institution did not provide an FTE then the reported FTE was set to the estimated FTE.</t></si><si><t>Doctor's-professional practice student FTE

Doctor's degree - professional practice  A doctor's degree that is conferred upon completion of a program providing the knowledge and skills for the recognition, credential, or license required for professional practice. The degree is awarded after a period of study such that the total time to the degree, including both pre-professional and professional preparation, equals at least six full-time equivalent academic years. Some of these degrees were formerly classified as first-professional and may include: Chiropractic (D.C. or D.C.M.); Dentistry (D.D.S. or D.M.D.); Law (L.L.B. or J.D.); Medicine (M.D.); Optometry (O.D.); Osteopathic Medicine (D.O); Pharmacy (Pharm.D.); Podiatry (D.P.M., Pod.D., D.P.); or, Veterinary Medicine (D.V.M.), and others, as designated by the awarding institution.</t></si><si><t>Imputation code values</t></si><si><t>This worksheet lists the code values for all imputation flag variables.</t></si><si><t>Code values for item imputation variables Xvarname</t></si><si><t>CodeValue</t></si><si><t>ValueLabel</t></si><si><t>A</t></si><si><t>B</t></si><si><t>Institution left item blank</t></si><si><t>C</t></si><si><t>Analyst corrected reported value</t></si><si><t>D</t></si><si><t>Do not know</t></si><si><t>G</t></si><si><t>Data generated from other data values</t></si><si><t>H</t></si><si><t>Value not derived - data not usable</t></si><si><t>J</t></si><si><t>Logical imputation</t></si><si><t>K</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Ratio adjustment </t></si><si><t>L</t></si><si><t>Imputed using the Group Median procedure</t></si><si><t>Imputed using Nearest Neighbor procedure</t></si><si><t>P</t></si><si><t>Imputed using Carry Forward procedure</t></si><si><t>R</t></si><si><t>Reported</t></si><si><t>Z</t></si><si><t>Implied zero;</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">This file contains data on instructional activity measured in total credit and/or contact hours delivered by institutions during a 12-month period.  The credit hour and contact hour activity data are used to derive 12-month full-time equivalent enrollments for both undergraduate and graduate levels.
</t></si><si><t/></si><si><t>Instructional activity data may be reported on Part F in units of contact hours or credit hours. Please indicate which units are used by the institution to measure instructional activity</t></si><si><t>(Final/revised release)</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve"> Provisional release:</t></si><si><t>November 2016</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Final/revised release:</t></si><si><t>EFIA2015_RV</t></si><si><t>FrequenciesRV</t></si><si><t>This worksheet contains the code values for of all categorical variables in the data file. It also lists the frequency and percent distribution for each code value by variable.(final/revised release)</t></si><si><t>StatisticsRV</t></si><si><t>This worksheet lists the sum, mean, minimum and maximum values of all continuous variables in the data file. (final/revised release)</t></si><si><t>This worksheet contains the code values for of all categorical variables in the data file. It also lists the frequency and percent distribution for each code value by variable.(provisional release)</t></si><si><t>This worksheet lists the sum, mean, minimum and maximum values of all continuous variables in the data file. (provisional release)</t></si><si><t>November 2017</t></si></sst>